<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>HPCC Service Status</title>
    <description>We'll post information about ICER's system downtimes,  updates, new features, and other information for the ICER user community here.
</description>
    <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//</link>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.icer.msu.edu//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2025 00:50:43 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2025 00:50:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.2.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>OnDemand Portal Update on Thursday 8/7 - UPDATED</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;UPDATE 8:37PM: The OnDemand server is currently experiencing an issue mounting the GPFS filesystem and is unavailable to users. We are working to resolve this issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At 8:00PM on Thursday, August 7th, ICER’s OnDemand portal will undergo a minor version update. This update primarily includes bug fixes. If you have any questions about this update or encounter any issues with the OnDemand portal following the update, &lt;a href=&quot;https://contact.icer.msu.edu/&quot;&gt;please contact us&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 23:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2025/08/07/OnDemand-Update</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2025/08/07/OnDemand-Update</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>maintenance</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Brief Slurm Outage on Thursday 8/7 - RESOLVED</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;RESOLVED 8:30PM: The Slurm controller and database servers are back online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At 8:15PM on Thursday, August 7th, ICER’s Slurm scheduling and database servers will go offline to undergo a brief migration to new hardware. This migration is expected to take less than 15 minutes. During this time, new jobs may not be queued and no new jobs will start. Running jobs will be unaffected. Client commands (e.g. sacct, squeue, sbatch) will be unavailable during the migration. If you have any questions about this migration or encounter any issues with Slurm servers following the update, &lt;a href=&quot;https://contact.icer.msu.edu/&quot;&gt;please contact us&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 23:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2025/08/07/Brief-Slurm-Outage</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2025/08/07/Brief-Slurm-Outage</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>maintenance</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Gateway Node Operating System Upgrades - RESOLVED 8/7/2025</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;RESOLVED 8/7/2025 - Maintenance on the gateway nodes is complete. Please let us know by submitting a ticket through our &lt;a href=&quot;https://contact.icer.msu.edu/contact&quot;&gt;Contact Forms&lt;/a&gt; if you experience any issues logging into the system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thursday 08/07/2025 at 6:00 PM, we will be upgrading the operating systems on one of our gateway nodes. If you experience a timeout while attempting to connect to the HPCC, please try again after a short (3-5 min) delay or use our &lt;a href=&quot;https://ondemand.hpcc.msu.edu&quot;&gt;open ondemand instance&lt;/a&gt;. If you continue to have difficulty logging into HPCC resources or notice any new issues with your connection to the HPCC, please let us know by submitting a ticket through our &lt;a href=&quot;https://contact.icer.msu.edu/contact&quot;&gt;Contact Forms&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2025/08/06/gateway-ubuntu-upgrade</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2025/08/06/gateway-ubuntu-upgrade</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>maintenance</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Gateway Node Reboots - August 5 to 8, 2025</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Beginning the evening of August 5, ICER will be rebooting each of our gateway nodes to upgrade the infrastructure powering the gateways. These reboots are expected to take 10 minutes each, and will be completed each day at 6PM based on the schedule below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First gateway  8/5/2025 @6pm
Second gateway 8/6/2025 @6pm
Third gateway  8/7/2025 @6pm
Fourth gateway 8/8/2025 @6pm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Users will be alerted before each reboot. If you get a connection timeout when trying to connect to the HPCC through ssh, please wait a few minutes and try again.  If you have continued issues connecting, please &lt;a href=&quot;https://contact.icer.msu.edu/&quot;&gt;open a ticket&lt;/a&gt;. This blog post will be updated once all gateway maintenance is complete.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 19:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2025/08/04/gateway-maintenance</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2025/08/04/gateway-maintenance</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>maintenance</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Home Filesystem Maintenance at 6:30AM on 7/29/25 - RESOLVED 7/29/2025</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;RESOLVED 7/29/2025 - This maintenance was completed the morning of July 29, 2025.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Tuesday, July 29th, at 6:30AM, the home filesystem will be upgraded to improve performance and reliability of the system. No outage or downtime are anticipated, and the upgrade is scheduled to be complete before 8AM. This blog post will be updated when the home filesystem upgrade is complete.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2025 17:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2025/07/25/home-storage-maintenance</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2025/07/25/home-storage-maintenance</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>maintenance</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Slurm Database Outage at 8:00PM on 7/29/25 - RESOLVED</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;RESOLVED: The Slurm database server is back online&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Tuesday, July 29th, at 8:00PM, the Slurm database will go offline in order to allocate more memory to the host server. This is being done to improve overall server stability and responsiveness. The database is expected to be offline for approximately 30 minutes. During this outage, the sacct and sacctmgr commands will be unavailable, as will managing buy-in account memberships through the buyin_status powertool. Other client commands (e.g. squeue, srun, sbatch, salloc) will continue to work as expected. Jobs may still be submitted and will start normally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about this outage or you experience issues following this outage, &lt;a href=&quot;https://contact.icer.msu.edu/&quot;&gt;please contact us&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2025/07/24/SLURM-Database-Server-Outage</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2025/07/24/SLURM-Database-Server-Outage</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>maintenance</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Data Center Water Cooling Problems - RESOLVED 7/21/2025</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;UPDATE: 7/21/2025 - IPF installed a temporary chiller to resume water cooling for our AMD24 cluster.  The cluster is back online and fully functional.  We will need to do a short shutdown to switch to the main chiller after it is fixed, but that could be months down the road.  Will send out annoucements when that happens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UPDATE: 7/15/2025 - IPF is currently in the process of obtaining a rental water chiller and organizing the water and power feeds.  They are optimistic of having a working solution by end of this week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UPDATE: 7/11/2025 - The water cooling system is getting too warm and nfh nodes are being shutdown.  IPF and vendor have identified a rental to restore service, timeline for installation still TBD.  Everyone is working hard to get this ASAP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starting at 12:30am 7/9/2025, we experienced multiple failed components on our water cooling system.  Waiting on IPF for solutions or alternatives.  We are told it could be multiple weeks for a fix.  We are shutting down AMD24 CPU nodes in hopes the AMD24 GPU nodes will remain in a safe operating temperature.  We will provide updates as we learn more.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2025/07/09/water-cooling-problems</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2025/07/09/water-cooling-problems</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>maintenance</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Scratch Filesystem Errors</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Due to an issue with the scratch filesystem, users may notice intermittent errors when attempting to write data to their scratch directory. These errors will state that the scratch filesystem or device is out of space. The ICER system administration team is actively working with our storage vendor to resolve these errors and we will post additional updates as soon as we have more information.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 12:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2025/07/01/scratch-errors</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2025/07/01/scratch-errors</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>maintenance</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Old Home Directory Maintenance Beginning Monday 6/23/25</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;On Monday, June 23, 2025, we will begin consolidating all data remaining on the old home filesystem to make room for additional research space storage. While many of you who were moved to the new filesystem in the past several weeks still have access to this data, you should not be using the old home filesystem for any running jobs or active workflows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will continue to maintain access to your old home directory data throughout the summer, but may notice intermittent pauses in your access while the data is being consolidated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information on the new home filesystem, please consult &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.icer.msu.edu/Home_Migration/&quot;&gt;our documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions, please contact us using our &lt;a href=&quot;https://contact.icer.msu.edu/contact&quot;&gt;contact form&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2025 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2025/06/19/Old_HomeDirectory_Maintenance</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2025/06/19/Old_HomeDirectory_Maintenance</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>maintenance</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Security Patch Applied on 6/19/25</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;On 19 June, 2025 a security patch was applied to the system. Although no user impact is expected, please open a ticket using our contact page https://contact.icer.msu.edu/contact if you encounter any issues.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2025/06/19/Security_patch_applied</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2025/06/19/Security_patch_applied</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>maintenance</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
