<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>HPCC Service Status</title>
    <description>We'll post information about ICER's system downtimes,  updates, new features, and other information for the ICER user community here.
</description>
    <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//</link>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.icer.msu.edu//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 12:14:46 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 12:14:46 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.2.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>OpenOnDemand is Down</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Due to a network change for an update, OpenOnDemand is down.  Working to restore access ASAP.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2025/10/10/OOD-down</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2025/10/10/OOD-down</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>maintenance</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Scratch Filesystem Errors and Timeouts</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A hardware issue is currently affecting the performance of the scratch filesystem on the HPCC. We are working with our vendor to resolve this issue. Scratch may need to be taken offline at some point in the next few weeks to resolve the error, and we will coordinate with users to ensure the least amount of disruption to workflows. More information on scheduled maintenance will be provided as soon as it is available. If you are currently experiencing issues reading or writing to the scratch filesystem, please let us know via our &lt;a href=&quot;https://contact.icer.msu.edu/contact&quot;&gt;Contact Form&lt;/a&gt;, and we can work with you on alternatives to support your workflow until this issue is resolved.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 16:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2025/10/07/Scratch-Filesystem-Errors</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2025/10/07/Scratch-Filesystem-Errors</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>maintenance</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>2025-09-26 Rebooting dev-amd20 and dev-amd24 at 1:25 AM on 9/27</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Both dev-amd20 and dev-amd24 will be rebooted at 1:25 AM on Saturday, September 27th. These reboots are being performed to address a filesystem stability issue.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2025/09/26/Development-Node-Reboot</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2025/09/26/Development-Node-Reboot</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>maintenance</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>GPU Development Node Updates</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;For system stability and better utilization of shared resources, today we are implementing an additional procedure on our GPU development nodes to ensure any long running GPU processes (greater than 2 hours) are automatically removed from the development node.  &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.icer.msu.edu/development_nodes/&quot;&gt;For more information on our development nodes, please see our documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 13:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2025/09/23/dev-node-gpu-update</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2025/09/23/dev-node-gpu-update</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>maintenance</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Home Filesystem Maintenance at 7AM on Monday 9/8/25 and Friday 9/12/25 - RESOLVED 9/12/25</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;RESOLVED 9/12/2025 - All planned filesystem updates are complete.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UPDATE 9/8/2025 - The initial upgrade completed successfully. We will resume the upgrade process Friday morning at 7AM. This message will be updated once the last upgrade process completes Friday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Monday, September 8th, at 7AM, the home filesystem will be upgraded in preparation for further updates on Friday, September 12,to help increase performance of home directories. No outage or downtime are anticipated. This blog post will be updated when this upgrade is complete.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 13:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2025/09/05/home-storage-maintenance</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2025/09/05/home-storage-maintenance</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>maintenance</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>SSH-Connection-permission denied-Errors</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Some HPCC users are experiencing ‘permission denied’ errors when entering their MSU Password while attempting to connect through a local terminal using the ‘ssh’ command. This is likely a result of campus network authentication issues. There is no immediate resolution to this issue, and ICER recommends that these users transition to SSH Key – based authentication. Detailed instructions can be found here:  &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.icer.msu.edu/SSH_Key-Based_Authentication/&quot;&gt;SSH Key – Based Authentication&lt;/a&gt;.
All users may continue to connect to the HPCC through the OnDemand Web Portal for general use and SSH Key Setup. Detailed instructions can be found here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.icer.msu.edu/Open_OnDemand/&quot;&gt;OnDemand Web Portal&lt;/a&gt;.
If you require additional assistance with SSH Key – Based Authentication, please submit a request through our &lt;a href=&quot;https://contact.icer.msu.edu/contact&quot;&gt;Contact Form&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2025/08/29/SSH-Connection-permission-denied-Errors</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2025/08/29/SSH-Connection-permission-denied-Errors</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>maintenance</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Gateway Node Operating System Upgrades - RESOLVED 8/21/2025</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;RESOLVED: 8/21/2025 - The gateway operating system upgrades are complete. Please report any issues through our &lt;a href=&quot;https://contact.icer.msu.edu/contact&quot;&gt;Contact Forms&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UPDATE: 8/20/2025 - As of 8/21/2025 6:00 PM, MobaXterm version v22.0 or later will be required to access the HPCC. MobaXterm users should update to the latest version or ensure they are using at least version v22.0.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thursday 08/21/2025 at 6:00 PM, we will be upgrading the operating systems on our gateway nodes. Users will see an alert notification in their terminal before the system is shut down to allow users sufficient time to save their work. If you experience a timeout while attempting to connect to the HPCC, please try again after a short (3-5 min) delay or use our &lt;a href=&quot;https://ondemand.hpcc.msu.edu&quot;&gt;open ondemand instance&lt;/a&gt;. If you continue to have difficulty logging into HPCC resources or notice any new issues with your connection to the HPCC, please let us know by submitting a ticket through our &lt;a href=&quot;https://contact.icer.msu.edu/contact&quot;&gt;Contact Forms&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2025/08/18/gateway-operating-system-upgrade</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2025/08/18/gateway-operating-system-upgrade</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>maintenance</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Gateway Configuration Updates - 8/15/2025</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As part of our efforts to improve security, we will be making some changes to the configuration of our gateway nodes on Monday August 18th, 2025. Initially, these changes will only affect a single gateway node (gateway-00.hpcc.msu.edu), but eventually all gateway nodes will have the updated configuration. If you experience an error in connecting to the hpcc after Monday, you may need to update your ssh client. As always, please submit a &lt;a href=&quot;https://contact.icer.msu.edu&quot;&gt;ticket&lt;/a&gt; if you have any questions or experience an ongoing issue connecting to the HPCC.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2025/08/15/Gateway-configuration-updates</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2025/08/15/Gateway-configuration-updates</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>maintenance</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Intel16 Cluster Has Been Retired</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;All intel16 nodes have been retired and removed from the cluster configuration. This includes &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;lac&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;vim&lt;/code&gt; nodes, as well as all &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;k80&lt;/code&gt; GPUs. Buy-in accounts that contained only &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;intel16&lt;/code&gt; nodes have been disabled and members’ default accounts updated to other buy-ins or to the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;general&lt;/code&gt; account. If you have any questions about this change or encounter any issues, &lt;a href=&quot;https://contact.icer.msu.edu/&quot;&gt;please contact us&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2025/08/12/Intel16-Retired</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2025/08/12/Intel16-Retired</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>maintenance</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>OnDemand Portal Offline - RESOLVED</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;RESOLVED 8/8: The OnDemand portal is available again and mounting the GPFS filesystem properly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The OnDemand portal is currently unavailable. Following the OnDemand server’s migration to new underlying compute hardware, the GPFS filesystem failed to mount properly, preventing the portal from coming online. We are currently working to resolve this issue as soon as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2025 15:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2025/08/08/OnDemand-Offline</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2025/08/08/OnDemand-Offline</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>maintenance</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
