<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ICER Announcements Blog</title>
    <description>We'll post information about ICER's system downtimes,  updates, new features, and other information for the ICER user community here.
</description>
    <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//</link>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.icer.msu.edu//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 00:02:57 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 00:02:57 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.2.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Home filesystem issues causing login problems</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;At approximately 11:10 AM on 5/10/2024 we experienced a transient outage while conducting upgrades and hardware refresh of our Home filesystem.  This outage may have caused login issues or stale filemounts.  Services were restored after approximately 15 minutes and home directories should be available again.  If you countinue to experience issues with your home directory, &lt;a href=&quot;https://contact.icer.msu.edu/&quot;&gt;please contact us&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 03:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/2024/05/10/Filesystem_issues</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/2024/05/10/Filesystem_issues</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>System Reboots Thursday May 9</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;On Thursday May 9 the following systems will be rebooted from 10-12am:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;gateway-[00-04]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;globus-02&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;rdpgw&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;openondemand&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will briefly impact login services, Globus, and Openondemand.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 07:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/2024/05/06/System-Reboots</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/2024/05/06/System-Reboots</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Home filesystem issue UPDATED 5/3/2024 5:00PM</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;UPDATE (5/3/2024 5:00 pm) - The issue has been resolved and all services should be available. If you encounter any additional issues, &lt;a href=&quot;https://contact.icer.msu.edu/&quot;&gt;please contact us&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At approximately 4:30PM on 5/3/24, we started having an issue with our home filesystem that is impacting operations related to home directories, including logins and OnDemand. This appears to be a network issue that we are investigating and will post an update once we have additional information.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 07:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/2024/05/03/Home-Directory-Problems</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/2024/05/03/Home-Directory-Problems</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Home filesystem issue causing login problems - UPDATED 5/2/2024 12:30 pm</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;UPDATE (5/2/2024 12:30 pm) - File system and connectivity issues have been resolved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UPDATE (4/25/2024 3:40 pm) - We are still receiving reports of connection and storage issues. Samba authentication is also currently down. We are working to resolve these issues. If you encounter any additional issues, &lt;a href=&quot;https://contact.icer.msu.edu/&quot;&gt;please contact us&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UPDATE (4/25/2024 1:00 pm) - We are still receiving reports of connection and storage issues, specifically localized around dev-amd20. We are working to resolve the issue. Please use different development nodes in the meantime.  If you encounter any additional issues, &lt;a href=&quot;https://contact.icer.msu.edu/&quot;&gt;please contact us&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UPDATE (4/25/2024 11:45 am) - We have resolved slowdown issues related to the file system on the cluster. If you encounter any additional issues, &lt;a href=&quot;https://contact.icer.msu.edu/&quot;&gt;please contact us&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UPDATE (4/25/2024 8:45 am) - We have received reports of slow responses to commands on the system and are investigating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UPDATE (4/24/2024 4:05 pm) - During upgrade and hardware refresh of our home filesystem, an unforseen error caused an outage.  The problem node has been removed from service and all services should be available.  If you encounter any additional issues, &lt;a href=&quot;https://contact.icer.msu.edu/&quot;&gt;please contact us&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At approximately 3:00 pm on 4/24/24 we started having an issue with our home filesystem that is impacting logins.  We are investigating and will post an update once we have additional information.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 15:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/2024/05/02/Filesystem_issues</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/2024/05/02/Filesystem_issues</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Scheduler Reboot at 10:00AM on 3/19/24</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;At 10:00AM on Tuesday, March 19th, the SLURM scheduling server will go offline for a reboot. This reboot is necessary to apply updates to the underlying hardware that hosts the scheduler. The scheduler is expected to be offline for roughly 15 minutes. During this time, jobs may not be submitted and scheduler specific client commands will not work (e.g. squeue, sbatch, etc). Running jobs will not be affected. If you have any questions about this outage, &lt;a href=&quot;https://contact.icer.msu.edu/&quot;&gt;please contact us&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 12:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/2024/03/18/SLURM_Controller_Reboot</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/2024/03/18/SLURM_Controller_Reboot</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Scheduler Reboot at 10:00AM on 3/18/24</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;At 10:00AM on Monday, March 18th, the SLURM scheduling server will go offline for a reboot. This reboot is necessary to apply updates to the underlying hardware that hosts the scheduler. The scheduler is expected to be offline for roughly 15 minutes. During this time, jobs may not be submitted and scheduler specific client commands will not work (e.g. squeue, sbatch, etc). Running jobs will not be affected. If you have any questions about this outage, &lt;a href=&quot;https://contact.icer.msu.edu/&quot;&gt;please contact us&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 12:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/2024/03/15/SLURM_Controller_Reboot</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/2024/03/15/SLURM_Controller_Reboot</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Scratch space not acccessible via OnDemand</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;UPDATE (3/1/2024) - Access to scratch via OnDemand has been restored&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are aware of an issue where users are unable to access their scratch space via OnDeamnd. We are currently looking into the issue and will post further updates here. Scratch space is still accessible through SSH&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/2024/03/01/Scratch_OnDemand_Problem</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/2024/03/01/Scratch_OnDemand_Problem</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>VSCode updates will break access</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This post applies to users of VS Code that SSH into the ICER HPCC from their own copy of VS Code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Error message:
“This machine does not meet Visual Studio Code Server’s prerequisites, expected either…:   - find GLIBC &amp;gt;= v2.28.0 (but found v2.17.0 instead) for GNU environments”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Details
Microsoft recently updated Visual Studio Code to version 1.86, and it is no longer compatible with the operating system we use at ICER. The change note that lists the change is here https://code.visualstudio.com/updates/v1_86#_engineering (scroll down to “Linux minimum requirements update”) Although we plan to upgrade our operating system this year, in the meantime there are two solutions to this incompatibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Solutions&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) Use our code server app in OnDemand (Interactive Apps -&amp;gt; Code Server (beta)) You can request compute nodes to work on for a specified amount of time, and use VS Code in your browser.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) Downgrade to the previous 1.85 version of VS Code and disable automatic updates. You can access the previous version here https://code.visualstudio.com/updates/v1_85 (see the Downloads section for a version for your PC or Mac)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/2024/02/01/VSCode_Update_Problem</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/2024/02/01/VSCode_Update_Problem</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Minor SLURM Update on 01/11/24</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;On Thursday, January 11th, we will be deploying a minor update to the SLURM scheduling software. This update will bring ICER to the latest minor revision of SLURM 23.02. Running and queued jobs should not be affected. No interruptions are expected to client command functionality (e.g. squeue, sbatch, sacct). If you have any questions about this update or you experience issues following this update, &lt;a href=&quot;https://contact.icer.msu.edu/&quot;&gt;please contact us&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2024/01/05/Minor-SLURM-Update</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2024/01/05/Minor-SLURM-Update</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>maintenance</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Winter Break Limited Coverage</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;There will be limited coverage while MSU observes winter break from December 22, 2023 through January 2, 2024.  The system will continue to run jobs and be monitored for emergency issues.  Tickets will be sorted by priority on January 3 when our team returns to work after the holiday break.
If you have any questions, &lt;a href=&quot;https://contact.icer.msu.edu/&quot;&gt;please contact us&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/2023/12/13/Winter-Break-Hours</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/2023/12/13/Winter-Break-Hours</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
