<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>HPCC Service Status</title>
    <description>We'll post information about ICER's system downtimes,  updates, new features, and other information for the ICER user community here.
</description>
    <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//</link>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.icer.msu.edu//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 20:53:08 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 20:53:08 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.2.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Home Filesystem Maintenance at 7AM on Monday 9/8/25 and Friday 9/12/25 - UPDATED 9/8/25</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;UPDATE 9/8/2025 - The initial upgrade completed successfully. We will resume the upgrade process Friday morning at 7AM. This message will be updated once the last upgrade process completes Friday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Monday, September 8th, at 7AM, the home filesystem will be upgraded in preparation for further updates on Friday, September 12,to help increase performance of home directories. No outage or downtime are anticipated. This blog post will be updated when this upgrade is complete.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 13:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2025/09/05/home-storage-maintenance</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2025/09/05/home-storage-maintenance</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>maintenance</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>SSH-Connection-permission denied-Errors</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Some HPCC users are experiencing ‘permission denied’ errors when entering their MSU Password while attempting to connect through a local terminal using the ‘ssh’ command. This is likely a result of campus network authentication issues. There is no immediate resolution to this issue, and ICER recommends that these users transition to SSH Key – based authentication. Detailed instructions can be found here:  &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.icer.msu.edu/SSH_Key-Based_Authentication/&quot;&gt;SSH Key – Based Authentication&lt;/a&gt;.
All users may continue to connect to the HPCC through the OnDemand Web Portal for general use and SSH Key Setup. Detailed instructions can be found here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.icer.msu.edu/Open_OnDemand/&quot;&gt;OnDemand Web Portal&lt;/a&gt;.
If you require additional assistance with SSH Key – Based Authentication, please submit a request through our &lt;a href=&quot;https://contact.icer.msu.edu/contact&quot;&gt;Contact Form&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2025/08/29/SSH-Connection-permission-denied-Errors</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2025/08/29/SSH-Connection-permission-denied-Errors</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>maintenance</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Gateway Node Operating System Upgrades - RESOLVED 8/21/2025</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;RESOLVED: 8/21/2025 - The gateway operating system upgrades are complete. Please report any issues through our &lt;a href=&quot;https://contact.icer.msu.edu/contact&quot;&gt;Contact Forms&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UPDATE: 8/20/2025 - As of 8/21/2025 6:00 PM, MobaXterm version v22.0 or later will be required to access the HPCC. MobaXterm users should update to the latest version or ensure they are using at least version v22.0.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thursday 08/21/2025 at 6:00 PM, we will be upgrading the operating systems on our gateway nodes. Users will see an alert notification in their terminal before the system is shut down to allow users sufficient time to save their work. If you experience a timeout while attempting to connect to the HPCC, please try again after a short (3-5 min) delay or use our &lt;a href=&quot;https://ondemand.hpcc.msu.edu&quot;&gt;open ondemand instance&lt;/a&gt;. If you continue to have difficulty logging into HPCC resources or notice any new issues with your connection to the HPCC, please let us know by submitting a ticket through our &lt;a href=&quot;https://contact.icer.msu.edu/contact&quot;&gt;Contact Forms&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2025/08/18/gateway-operating-system-upgrade</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2025/08/18/gateway-operating-system-upgrade</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>maintenance</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Gateway Configuration Updates - 8/15/2025</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As part of our efforts to improve security, we will be making some changes to the configuration of our gateway nodes on Monday August 18th, 2025. Initially, these changes will only affect a single gateway node (gateway-00.hpcc.msu.edu), but eventually all gateway nodes will have the updated configuration. If you experience an error in connecting to the hpcc after Monday, you may need to update your ssh client. As always, please submit a &lt;a href=&quot;https://contact.icer.msu.edu&quot;&gt;ticket&lt;/a&gt; if you have any questions or experience an ongoing issue connecting to the HPCC.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2025/08/15/Gateway-configuration-updates</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2025/08/15/Gateway-configuration-updates</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>maintenance</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Intel16 Cluster Has Been Retired</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;All intel16 nodes have been retired and removed from the cluster configuration. This includes &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;lac&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;vim&lt;/code&gt; nodes, as well as all &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;k80&lt;/code&gt; GPUs. Buy-in accounts that contained only &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;intel16&lt;/code&gt; nodes have been disabled and members’ default accounts updated to other buy-ins or to the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;general&lt;/code&gt; account. If you have any questions about this change or encounter any issues, &lt;a href=&quot;https://contact.icer.msu.edu/&quot;&gt;please contact us&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2025/08/12/Intel16-Retired</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2025/08/12/Intel16-Retired</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>maintenance</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>OnDemand Portal Offline - RESOLVED</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;RESOLVED 8/8: The OnDemand portal is available again and mounting the GPFS filesystem properly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The OnDemand portal is currently unavailable. Following the OnDemand server’s migration to new underlying compute hardware, the GPFS filesystem failed to mount properly, preventing the portal from coming online. We are currently working to resolve this issue as soon as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2025 15:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2025/08/08/OnDemand-Offline</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2025/08/08/OnDemand-Offline</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>maintenance</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>OnDemand Portal Update on Thursday 8/7 - RESOLVED</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;RESOLVED 8/8: The OnDemand server is back online and mounting the GPFS filesystem properly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UPDATE 8:37PM: The OnDemand server is currently experiencing an issue mounting the GPFS filesystem and is unavailable to users. We are working to resolve this issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At 8:00PM on Thursday, August 7th, ICER’s OnDemand portal will undergo a minor version update. This update primarily includes bug fixes. If you have any questions about this update or encounter any issues with the OnDemand portal following the update, &lt;a href=&quot;https://contact.icer.msu.edu/&quot;&gt;please contact us&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2025 15:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2025/08/08/OnDemand-Update</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2025/08/08/OnDemand-Update</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>maintenance</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Brief Slurm Outage on Thursday 8/7 - RESOLVED</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;RESOLVED 8:30PM: The Slurm controller and database servers are back online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At 8:15PM on Thursday, August 7th, ICER’s Slurm scheduling and database servers will go offline to undergo a brief migration to new hardware. This migration is expected to take less than 15 minutes. During this time, new jobs may not be queued and no new jobs will start. Running jobs will be unaffected. Client commands (e.g. sacct, squeue, sbatch) will be unavailable during the migration. If you have any questions about this migration or encounter any issues with Slurm servers following the update, &lt;a href=&quot;https://contact.icer.msu.edu/&quot;&gt;please contact us&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 23:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2025/08/07/Brief-Slurm-Outage</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2025/08/07/Brief-Slurm-Outage</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>maintenance</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Gateway Node Operating System Upgrades - RESOLVED 8/7/2025</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;RESOLVED 8/7/2025 - Maintenance on the gateway nodes is complete. Please let us know by submitting a ticket through our &lt;a href=&quot;https://contact.icer.msu.edu/contact&quot;&gt;Contact Forms&lt;/a&gt; if you experience any issues logging into the system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thursday 08/07/2025 at 6:00 PM, we will be upgrading the operating systems on one of our gateway nodes. If you experience a timeout while attempting to connect to the HPCC, please try again after a short (3-5 min) delay or use our &lt;a href=&quot;https://ondemand.hpcc.msu.edu&quot;&gt;open ondemand instance&lt;/a&gt;. If you continue to have difficulty logging into HPCC resources or notice any new issues with your connection to the HPCC, please let us know by submitting a ticket through our &lt;a href=&quot;https://contact.icer.msu.edu/contact&quot;&gt;Contact Forms&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2025/08/06/gateway-ubuntu-upgrade</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2025/08/06/gateway-ubuntu-upgrade</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>maintenance</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Gateway Node Reboots - August 5 to 8, 2025</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Beginning the evening of August 5, ICER will be rebooting each of our gateway nodes to upgrade the infrastructure powering the gateways. These reboots are expected to take 10 minutes each, and will be completed each day at 6PM based on the schedule below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First gateway  8/5/2025 @6pm
Second gateway 8/6/2025 @6pm
Third gateway  8/7/2025 @6pm
Fourth gateway 8/8/2025 @6pm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Users will be alerted before each reboot. If you get a connection timeout when trying to connect to the HPCC through ssh, please wait a few minutes and try again.  If you have continued issues connecting, please &lt;a href=&quot;https://contact.icer.msu.edu/&quot;&gt;open a ticket&lt;/a&gt;. This blog post will be updated once all gateway maintenance is complete.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 19:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2025/08/04/gateway-maintenance</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2025/08/04/gateway-maintenance</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>maintenance</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
