<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>HPCC Service Status</title>
    <description>We'll post information about ICER's system downtimes,  updates, new features, and other information for the ICER user community here.
</description>
    <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//</link>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.icer.msu.edu//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 20:54:45 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 20:54:45 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.2.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Minor Network Configuration Change on 06/04/25</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;On the morning of Wednesday, June 4, we will be deploying a configuration change to our high-speed InfiniBand network. This is a minor change that should take around 15 minutes and is not expected to have any impact on the HPCC. An update to this announcement will be posted as soon as the maintenance is complete. If you have any questions about this change or you experience issues following this update, &lt;a href=&quot;https://contact.icer.msu.edu/&quot;&gt;please contact us&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2025/06/02/IB-Conf-Update</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2025/06/02/IB-Conf-Update</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>maintenance</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Minor SLURM Update on 05/29/25</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;On Thursday, May 29th, we will be deploying a minor update to the SLURM scheduling software. This update patches a security vulnerability and will allow us to re-enable buy-in account coordinator functionality. Running and queued jobs should not be affected. A brief interruption to client commands may be experienced (e.g. squeue, sbatch, sacct). If you have any questions about this update or you experience issues following this update, &lt;a href=&quot;https://contact.icer.msu.edu/&quot;&gt;please contact us&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2025/05/23/SLURM-Update</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2025/05/23/SLURM-Update</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>maintenance</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>HPCC Scheduled Downtime - Resolved on 5/14/2025 5:30pm</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update 5:30 PM 5/14&lt;/strong&gt; - Current status:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;gs21 has been returned to service, and all held jobs have been released. We have some open issues to address with the vendor but the system should operate as expected.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;research/ufs24 should be performing as normal. We are continuing to investigate to identify a root cause.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update 9 AM 5/14&lt;/strong&gt; - Current status:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Work on g21 / scratch with the vendor is continuing. We are checking the integrity of the system before returning to service.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We identified what appeared to be a source of the problem last night with ufs24/research. We have not seen any pauses since removing it last night. We have an open ticket with the vendor to confirm the root causes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update 4:15 PM 5/13&lt;/strong&gt; - Current status:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We have successfully attached the components of the scratch file system and are working with the vendor to scan and mount them.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ongoing home pauses should be limited. We have repaired the network link but are still seeing some slow performance. We are working with the vendor to resolve the issue.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;SchedMD has identified the cause of the Slurm outage. We have removed the responsible component.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update 12:00 PM 5/13&lt;/strong&gt; - Current status&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We are still working with the vendor for scratch (gs21); a component has failed in a way that is blocking the file system from mounting. The vendor is actively engaged.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Home pauses / IO delays should be reduced as most of the active AFM resynchronization has completed. We have identified a network link that we are investigating as the cause.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Affected RT tickets have been recreated.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;SchedMD has examined the Slurm issue and identified a potential cause; we have not seen a reoccurrence since.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update 4:00 PM 5/12&lt;/strong&gt; - Current status:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Work is progressing on restoring scratch (gs21) to service. We have successfully started all nodes and are working on rescanning the file system to bring it back online. We will update the status again tomorrow morning.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Users may notice long pauses when accessing their home directory or research spaces on gateways or OpenOnDemand due to the offsite resynchronization process. We are investigating the cause of the delays. Home directories that have been migrated to ffs24 should not be delayed on compute nodes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We have reverted the upgrade of the RT server due to front-end compatibility issues. If you submitted a ticket between Friday morning and this afternoon, we will recreate the ticket, possibly with a new ticket ID number.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We are tracking an issue with the Slurm server that may cause slurm commands like &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;squeue&lt;/code&gt; to become unresponsive. We have contacted the vendor and are investigating diagnostic data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Update 9:00AM 5/12 - To minimize the impact of the scratch outage, queued jobs referencing “gs21”, “scratch”, or “SCRATCH”, have been placed in a held state. This will show as the status “JobHeldUser”. If you have a job in this state that should be able to run without scratch, this hold can be released by running ‘scontrol release &lt;jobid&gt;'. These holds will be released when scratch is restored.&lt;/jobid&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Update 4:00PM 5/11 - HPCC is back online.  HPCC is working with our vendor to recover gs21 scratch space.  It suffered some problems during the earlier power and generator testing.  The cluster is being returned to production without /mnt/scratch.  We will provide updates as we work through with our vendor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Update 7:30PM 5/10 - ITS completed generator testing in the data center.  HPCC is still waiting on our provider to complete firewall updates, which would cause significant downtime during that process.  We are waiting on that before migrating back to production.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Update 11:00am 5/9 - HPCC has completed routine maintenance.  ITS was not able to complete the water cooling tests and those will need to be completed some day in the future.  Unfortunately we will remain down for the ITS data center power and generator testing on Saturday.  Their work is expected to be completed by 4:00PM on Saturday followed by us turning everything back on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Update 8:17am 5/9 - HPCC is in maintenance mode until Saturday evening.  You cannot login or run jobs until then.  Blog will be updated accordingly as time goes on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The HPCC will be unavailable on Friday, May 9th and Saturday, May 10th, 2025 for our regularly scheduled maintenance and IPF required power system testing. No jobs will run during this time and logins to gateway nodes will be disabled. Jobs that will not be completed before May 9th will not begin until after maintenance is complete. For example, if you submit a four day job three days before the maintenance outage, your job will be postponed and will not begin to run until after maintenance is completed. Jobs and logins will be resumed once the maintenance is complete.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/2025/05/11/HPCC_Scheduled_Downtime</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/2025/05/11/HPCC_Scheduled_Downtime</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>SLURM Database Outage at 10:00AM on 5/8/25 - RESOLVED</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;RESOLVED: The database upgrade completes without issue and the database is back online&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Thursday, May 8th, at 10:00AM, the SLURM database will go offline in preparation for an underlying operating system upgrade. The database is expected to be offline through the upcoming downtime. During this outage, the sacct client command will be unavailable for querying job information. Other client commands (e.g. squeue, srun, sbatch, salloc) will continue to work as expected. Jobs may still be submitted and will start normally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about this outage or you experience issues following this outage, &lt;a href=&quot;https://contact.icer.msu.edu/&quot;&gt;please contact us&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2025/05/05/SLURM-Database-Server-Outage</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2025/05/05/SLURM-Database-Server-Outage</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>maintenance</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Contact Form Outage - RESOLVED</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;UPDATE: 5/6/2025 8:30 PM - Contact form maintenance is completed and services have been restored.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://contact.icer.msu.edu&quot;&gt;ICER Contact From&lt;/a&gt; will be down Tuesday May 6th from 5pm-7pm for system upgrades.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/2025/05/05/Contact_Form_Outage</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/2025/05/05/Contact_Form_Outage</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Gateway ssh host key updates - RESOLVED</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;UPDATE: 4/17/2025 7:00 AM - Gateway node ssh host identification keys have been changed, please see documentation listed below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of ongoing system updates, our ssh gateway node host identification keys are changing.  Once these keys are changed, you will likely receive a warning that the host key has changed.  Please refer to our documentation for more details on ssh host keys and resolving this error (https://docs.icer.msu.edu/Resetting_Known_Hosts/).  You can find the most up to date list of ssh host keys in our documentation as well (https://docs.icer.msu.edu/Connect_to_HPCC_System/#current-ssh-host-identification-key-fingerprints).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2025/04/17/gateway-hostkey-change</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2025/04/17/gateway-hostkey-change</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>maintenance</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>2025-04-18 amd24 water cooling work</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;IPF will be performing work to test the water cooling system on Friday April 18th, 2025. We do not anticipate that it will impact users but there is a possiblity that workloads may be impacted.
We will update this blog when the window starts and end if there’s any disruption noticed.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 13:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/2025/04/16/water-cooling</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/2025/04/16/water-cooling</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Updates to Intel MPI - UPDATED</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;UPDATE 4/17/2025 12:00 PM - There have been reports that Intel MPI no longer works using &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;mpirun&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;mpiexec&lt;/code&gt;. While we are investigating the source of this issue, please switch to using the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;srun&lt;/code&gt; command as a workaround.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.icer.msu.edu/available_software/detail/impi/&quot;&gt;All Intel MPI modules&lt;/a&gt; have been rebuilt to allow usage with &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;srun&lt;/code&gt;. We encourage all users to use &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;srun&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.icer.msu.edu/Show_Job_Steps_by_sacct_and_srun_Commands/&quot;&gt;launch MPI programs&lt;/a&gt; moving forward. This should not impact any existing functionality, and all commands launched via &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;mpirun&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;mpiexec&lt;/code&gt; should continue to function normally (UPDATE: We have received reports that &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;mpirun&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;mpiexec&lt;/code&gt; are not functioning normally).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you see any issues using an Intel MPI module, please &lt;a href=&quot;https://contact.icer.msu.edu/contact&quot;&gt;contact us&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/update/2025/04/15/Updates-to-Intel-MPI</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/update/2025/04/15/Updates-to-Intel-MPI</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Minor SLURM Update on 04/03/25 - RESOLVED</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;UPDATE: 4/3/2025 11:00 AM - The update completed without issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Thursday, April 3rd, we will be deploying a minor update to the SLURM scheduling software. This update contains bug fixes to improve system stability. Running and queued jobs should not be affected. No interruptions are expected to client command functionality (e.g. squeue, sbatch, sacct). If you have any questions about this update or you experience issues following this update, &lt;a href=&quot;https://contact.icer.msu.edu/&quot;&gt;please contact us&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2025/04/01/Minor-SLURM-Update</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2025/04/01/Minor-SLURM-Update</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>maintenance</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Gateway Node Operating System Upgrades - RESOLVED 4/1/2025</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;RESOLVED: 4/1/2025 Maintenance has been completed.  If you experience issues logging into HPCC resources, please let us know by submitting a ticket through our &lt;a href=&quot;https://contact.icer.msu.edu/contact&quot;&gt;Contact Forms&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tuesday 04/01/2025 at 5:00 AM, we will be upgrading the operating systems on one of our gateway nodes.  If you experience a timeout while attempting to connect to the HPCC, please try again after a short (3-5 min) delay or use our &lt;a href=&quot;https://ondemand.hpcc.msu.edu&quot;&gt;open ondemand instance&lt;/a&gt;.  If you continue to have difficulty logging into HPCC resources, please let us know by submitting a ticket through our &lt;a href=&quot;https://contact.icer.msu.edu/contact&quot;&gt;Contact Forms&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2025 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2025/03/31/gateway-node-os-upgrade</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2025/03/31/gateway-node-os-upgrade</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>maintenance</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
