<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>HPCC Service Status</title>
    <description>We'll post information about ICER's system downtimes,  updates, new features, and other information for the ICER user community here.
</description>
    <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//</link>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.icer.msu.edu//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 15:17:48 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 15:17:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.2.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Minor SLURM Update on 01/09/25</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;On Thursday, January 9th, we will be deploying a minor update to the SLURM scheduling software. This update includes bug fixes to improve system stability. Running and queued jobs should not be affected. No interruptions are expected to client command functionality (e.g. squeue, sbatch, sacct). If you have any questions about this update or you experience issues following this update, &lt;a href=&quot;https://contact.icer.msu.edu/&quot;&gt;please contact us&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2025/01/07/Minor-SLURM-Update</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2025/01/07/Minor-SLURM-Update</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>maintenance</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Login issues - RESOLVED 1/2/2025</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;RESOLVED: All login gateways are now active.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are aware of login issues with SSH. These are caused by an outage of a single login gateway. We are working to resolve the issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Workaround: connect via our OnDemand portal at https://ondemand.hpcc.msu.edu/&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/2025/01/02/login-issues</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/2025/01/02/login-issues</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Winter Break Limited Coverage - RESOLVED 1/2/2025</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;RESOLVED: Support at ICER has returned to normal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There will be limited coverage while MSU observes winter break from December 24, 2024 through January 1, 2025.  The system will continue to run jobs and be monitored for emergency issues.  Tickets will be sorted by priority on January 2 when our team returns to work after the holiday break.
If you have any questions, &lt;a href=&quot;https://contact.icer.msu.edu/&quot;&gt;please contact us&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/2024/12/04/Winter-Break-Hours</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/2024/12/04/Winter-Break-Hours</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>HPCC Scheduled Downtime - RESOLVED 12/19/2024</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;RESOLVED: Maintenance is complete, thank you for your patience. Job submissions will continue to run after 5PM on 12/19. Please note that as the intel14 cluster has been retired, the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;intel14&lt;/code&gt; constraint must be removed from any jobs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The HPCC will be unavailable on Thursday, December 19th for our regularly scheduled maintenance.  No jobs will run during this time. Jobs that will not be completed before December 19th will not begin until after maintenance is complete. For example, if you submit a four day job three days before the maintenance outage, your job will be postponed and will not begin to run until after maintenance is completed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;High level overview of changes include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gateways host keys replacement&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cluster OS updates to improve stability and security&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Firmware and driver upgrades&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Final GPFS updates for summer storage replacement&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Slurm upgrade&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Network upgrades for new cluster&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bug fixes and other improvements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions, &lt;a href=&quot;https://contact.icer.msu.edu/&quot;&gt;please contact us&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/2024/12/03/Winter-Maintenance</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/2024/12/03/Winter-Maintenance</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Intel16 Cluster Currently Offline - RESOLVED 11/19/2024</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;RESOLVED: 11/19/2024 12:10PM - On 11/18/2024 ITS performed maintenance on a number of switches in the data center that required rebooting critical network infrastructure. After these reboots, several links connecting to the intel16 cluster did not recover. During this time, you may have also noticed brief pauses in OnDemand and on Gateway nodes. This morning we were able to work with ITS to re-establish connectivity to all intel16 nodes, and the intel16 cluster, along with all other nodes, are now back in production and running jobs via Slurm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Around 8:40pm on 11/18/2024 the intel16 cluster went offline due to a network outage and remains offline. Currently no jobs requesting to run on intel16 will be scheduled. We are troubleshooting this network outage with IT Services and will provide more information when it is available via an update to this blog post.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 13:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/2024/11/19/intel16-outage</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/2024/11/19/intel16-outage</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>MATLAB License issue - RESOLVED 10/31/2024</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;RESOLVED: 10/31/2024 5:15PM - The issue is resolved on development and compute nodes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UPDATE: 10/31/2024 4:00PM - The issue is resolved on development nodes. The fix is still being synced to compute nodes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ICER is investigating an issue with MATLAB licensing. When starting MATLAB, you may see an error message:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;License checkout failed.
License Manager Error -97
License Manager cannot start. 
Check that the ports specified in the license file are not already in use. 
Restarting your machine may clear the ports.

Troubleshoot this issue by visiting: 
https://www.mathworks.com/support/lme/97

Diagnostic Information:
Feature: MATLAB 
License path: /mnt/home/grosscra/.matlab/R2023b_licenses:/opt/software-current/2023.06/x86_64/generic/software/MATLAB/2023b/licenses/license.dat:/opt/software-current/2023.06/x86_64/generic/software/MATLAB/2023b/licenses/network.lic 
Licensing error: -97,121.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This issue is due to problems on our side which we are working to resolve. We will update this blog post accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/2024/10/31/MATLAB-License</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/2024/10/31/MATLAB-License</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Shared Module and Software Server Restart - RESOLVED 11/1/2024</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;RESOLVED: 11/1/2024 6:15 AM - The system restart is complete and all services should be online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At 6:00 AM on 1 November, 2024 we will restart our shared module and software server to improve performance.  Users may experience a delay or failure when logging into development nodes in the period of time while this system is restarting.  Slurm jobs should continue to run, but active connections to development nodes may experience momentary delays accessing the module system.  This restart should be completed within approximately 15 Minutes and updates will be posted here upon completion.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2024/10/31/module_software-fileserver-restart</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2024/10/31/module_software-fileserver-restart</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>maintenance</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Shared Software File Server Restart - RESOLVED 12:50 10/30/2024</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;RESOLVED: 1250 10/30/2024 - The system restart is complete and all services should be online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UPDATE: 11:00 10/30/2024 - The restart of the system will be scheduled for 12:30 PM on 10/30/2024.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At 11:00 AM on 30 October, 2024 we will be restarting our shared software server to improve performance.  Users may experience a delay or failure when logging into development nodes in the period of time while this system is restarting.  This restart should be completed within approximately 15 Minutes and updates will be posted here upon completion.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2024/10/30/software-fileserver-restart</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2024/10/30/software-fileserver-restart</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>maintenance</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ICER Web Application Login Error - RESOLVED 10/29/2024</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;UPDATE: 10/29/2024 - Logins to RT, OpenOnDemand, and Contact forms looks to be fully functional again. Values might be cached and you might need to clear your cache.  You can test by opening a private browser.  Email general@rt.hpcc.msu.edu if you still experience problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to a change earlier today with how the MSU ID office provides identity information to the CILogin service ICER uses to authenticate userIDs, some users may be unable to authenticate to ICER web applications, including OnDemand and the ICER contact forms. The issue with the information provided to CILogin has been resolved; however, now the MSU single sign on services must update all of their records, which may take several hours. If you receive the error message “user is not assigned the application” when attempting to login to ICER web services, you will need to wait for these records to update. SSH access to the HPCC is unaffected and will remain available during this time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 17:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/2024/10/28/ICER-Web-App-Login-Error</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/2024/10/28/ICER-Web-App-Login-Error</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ICER Contact Form UserID Information Lookup Error RESOLVED 10/29/2024</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://contact.icer.msu.edu/&quot;&gt;ICER contact form&lt;/a&gt; is currently experiencing a technical error retrieving userID information for some MSU accounts. This error may result in your inability to log new account or new research space requests. While we continue to troubleshoot this error, please use the &lt;a href=&quot;https://contact.icer.msu.edu/contact&quot;&gt;general contact form&lt;/a&gt; to submit your requests. This post will continue to be updated as we have more information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UPDATE 10/29/2024: Details in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.icer.msu.edu/announcement/2024/10/28/ICER-Web-App-Login-Error&quot;&gt;later blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 18:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/2024/10/25/UserID-Information-Lookup-Error</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/2024/10/25/UserID-Information-Lookup-Error</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
