<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>HPCC Service Status</title>
    <description>We'll post information about ICER's system downtimes,  updates, new features, and other information for the ICER user community here.
</description>
    <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//</link>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.icer.msu.edu//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 13:27:03 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 13:27:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.2.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Network errors - Problems connecting to HPCC - UPDATE 8:30AM</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;UPDATE: 8:30AM - Impact is resolved.  We identified core network hardware that had failed in a way that prevented High Availability to function properly.  This hardware has been removed from production while we work to get it replaced.  Users shouldn’t notice an impact, but we will be without redundancy on the core network until it is replaced.  ITS is working with the vendor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HPCC is experiencing network errors causing connection issues.  We are working with ITS networking team on a solution.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2025/11/07/Network-Errors</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2025/11/07/Network-Errors</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>maintenance</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>HPCC Scheduled Downtime</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The HPCC will be unavailable on Thursday, December 18th for our regularly scheduled maintenance.  No jobs will run during this time. Jobs that will not be completed before December 19th will not begin until after maintenance is complete. For example, if you submit a four day job three days before the maintenance outage, your job will be postponed and will not begin to run until after maintenance is completed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions, &lt;a href=&quot;https://contact.icer.msu.edu/&quot;&gt;please contact us&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/2025/11/04/Winter-Maintenance</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/2025/11/04/Winter-Maintenance</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Home Filesystem Maintenance at 630AM on Friday 11/7/25</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;On Friday, November 7th, at 6:30AM, a minor update will be applied to the home filesystem. No outage or performance impacts are anticipated. This blog will be updated once the upgrade is complete.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2025/11/03/home-filesystem-maintenance</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2025/11/03/home-filesystem-maintenance</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>maintenance</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Water Cooling Repairs for AMD24</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Multiple steps are needed to repair the water pumps from our failure on 7/9.  This Wednesday, Oct 15th, our primary water cooling loop will be taken down for 8 hours.  We anticipate AMD24 will remain in a safe operating zone during that time.  We will monitor it closely.  If the machines reach a high temperature we will need to take them offline and cancel jobs.  If this happens, we will work with impacted users.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2025/10/13/Water-Cooling-Repair</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2025/10/13/Water-Cooling-Repair</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>maintenance</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>OpenOnDemand is Down - RESOLVED </title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;RESOLVED: 11:13AM The network issue affecting the OnDemand portal has been resolved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to a network change for an update, OpenOnDemand is down.  Working to restore access ASAP.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2025/10/10/OOD-down</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2025/10/10/OOD-down</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>maintenance</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>UPDATED: Scratch Filesystem Errors and Timeouts - UPDATED 10/24/2025</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;UPDATE: 10/24/2025 3:41PM - The scratch filesystem is back online and all held jobs have been released.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UPDATE: 10/24/2025 - We were unable to hold some jobs that required scratch and those jobs failed as a result. We will reach out to the affected users to offer priority boosts on job resubmission.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UPDATE: 10/14/2025 - The scratch filesystem will be offline on Friday, 10/24/2025 from 8AM to 5PM to resolve this hardware issue. We will attempt to place any job referencing the scratch filesystem on hold during this time. However, if you have a job failure related to this emergency maintenance, please let us know via the &lt;a href=&quot;https://contact.icer.msu.edu/contact&quot;&gt;Contact Form&lt;/a&gt;, and we can work with you to reschedule the job as quickly as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A hardware issue is currently affecting the performance of the scratch filesystem on the HPCC. We are working with our vendor to resolve this issue. Scratch may need to be taken offline at some point in the next few weeks to resolve the error, and we will coordinate with users to ensure the least amount of disruption to workflows. More information on scheduled maintenance will be provided as soon as it is available. If you are currently experiencing issues reading or writing to the scratch filesystem, please let us know via our &lt;a href=&quot;https://contact.icer.msu.edu/contact&quot;&gt;Contact Form&lt;/a&gt;, and we can work with you on alternatives to support your workflow until this issue is resolved.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2025/10/07/Scratch-Filesystem-Errors</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2025/10/07/Scratch-Filesystem-Errors</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>maintenance</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>2025-09-26 Rebooting dev-amd20 and dev-amd24 at 1:25 AM on 9/27</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Both dev-amd20 and dev-amd24 will be rebooted at 1:25 AM on Saturday, September 27th. These reboots are being performed to address a filesystem stability issue.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2025/09/26/Development-Node-Reboot</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2025/09/26/Development-Node-Reboot</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>maintenance</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>GPU Development Node Updates</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;For system stability and better utilization of shared resources, today we are implementing an additional procedure on our GPU development nodes to ensure any long running GPU processes (greater than 2 hours) are automatically removed from the development node.  &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.icer.msu.edu/development_nodes/&quot;&gt;For more information on our development nodes, please see our documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 13:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2025/09/23/dev-node-gpu-update</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2025/09/23/dev-node-gpu-update</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>maintenance</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Home Filesystem Maintenance at 7AM on Monday 9/8/25 and Friday 9/12/25 - RESOLVED 9/12/25</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;RESOLVED 9/12/2025 - All planned filesystem updates are complete.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UPDATE 9/8/2025 - The initial upgrade completed successfully. We will resume the upgrade process Friday morning at 7AM. This message will be updated once the last upgrade process completes Friday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Monday, September 8th, at 7AM, the home filesystem will be upgraded in preparation for further updates on Friday, September 12,to help increase performance of home directories. No outage or downtime are anticipated. This blog post will be updated when this upgrade is complete.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 13:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2025/09/05/home-storage-maintenance</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2025/09/05/home-storage-maintenance</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>maintenance</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>SSH-Connection-permission denied-Errors</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Some HPCC users are experiencing ‘permission denied’ errors when entering their MSU Password while attempting to connect through a local terminal using the ‘ssh’ command. This is likely a result of campus network authentication issues. There is no immediate resolution to this issue, and ICER recommends that these users transition to SSH Key – based authentication. Detailed instructions can be found here:  &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.icer.msu.edu/SSH_Key-Based_Authentication/&quot;&gt;SSH Key – Based Authentication&lt;/a&gt;.
All users may continue to connect to the HPCC through the OnDemand Web Portal for general use and SSH Key Setup. Detailed instructions can be found here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.icer.msu.edu/Open_OnDemand/&quot;&gt;OnDemand Web Portal&lt;/a&gt;.
If you require additional assistance with SSH Key – Based Authentication, please submit a request through our &lt;a href=&quot;https://contact.icer.msu.edu/contact&quot;&gt;Contact Form&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2025/08/29/SSH-Connection-permission-denied-Errors</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2025/08/29/SSH-Connection-permission-denied-Errors</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>maintenance</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
