<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ICER Announcements Blog</title>
    <description>We'll post information about ICER's system downtimes,  updates, new features, and other information for the ICER user community here.
</description>
    <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//</link>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.icer.msu.edu//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2023 19:48:46 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2023 19:48:46 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.2.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Network Maintenance Planned for June 19, 2023 at 6:30PM</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;On Monday, June 19, 2023 at 6:30PM an update will be applied to a limited number of services in our networking infrastructure. A brief outage of only a few milliseconds for anyone attempting to connect to the HPCC at 6:30PM is anticipated while this update runs. An update to the blog will be posted when maintenance is complete.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2023 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/2023/06/15/Network-Maintenance-Planned-June-19-2023</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/2023/06/15/Network-Maintenance-Planned-June-19-2023</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Email Delivery Delays - June 5, 2023 - UPDATED</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;UPDATE: Email to ICER is now functioning again without errors or delays.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are currently seeing performance issues with one of the University’s third-party email providers. This issue is impacting email delivery to ICER, including contact form requests and responses to incident tickets. If you receive a bounceback error message upon emailing ICER, know that delivery for your message may be delayed, but delivery will be re-attempted for up to 5 days. We will post an update as soon as this issue is resolved.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2023 19:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/2023/06/05/Email-Delivery-Delay-Updated</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/2023/06/05/Email-Delivery-Delay-Updated</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Temporary Service Slowdown Possible - June 3, 2023</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;ICER users may notice slow network speeds from June 3 to June 7, 2023. In support of the XPRIZE competition, ICER will share significant HPCC resources during this timeframe which may result in service slowdowns&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/2023/06/01/XprizeSlowDown</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/2023/06/01/XprizeSlowDown</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Scheduled Home Filesystem Update - Tuesday, May 30, 2023</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;On Tuesday, May 30th at 10am EDT, we will be performing a minor version upgrade of our home filesystem. This process will take approximately two hours. While we will be performing the update with the filesystem online, there is a possibility that the cluster may briefly lose connection to the storage. Please take this into consideration for any jobs which will be running during this time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about these updates or you experience issues following these updates, &lt;a href=&quot;https://contact.icer.msu.edu/&quot;&gt;please contact us&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2023/05/23/GFPSUpdates</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2023/05/23/GFPSUpdates</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>maintenance</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Local File Quotas Are Now Set for /tmp and /var on All Nodes</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Beginning May 3, 2023, user quotas will be in place on all nodes for the /tmp and /var directories. All user accounts will be limited to 95% of the total /tmp partition space that is available on a particular node, and a 5GB limit on the /var partition. If a user account exceeds this quota, a 2 hour grace period will be allowed before the user account is no longer able to write to the /tmp or /var directory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about these changes &lt;a href=&quot;https://contact.icer.msu.edu/&quot;&gt;please contact us&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2023 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2023/05/02/New-Local-File-Quotas</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2023/05/02/New-Local-File-Quotas</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>maintenance</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Intel14 Nodes Now Dedicated to OnDemand</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Intel14 nodes have been removed from general queues and repurposed. A combined total of 2468 CPU cores and 15.66TB of memory has been dedicated to running jobs submitted through ICER’s installation of &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.icer.msu.edu/Open_OnDemand&quot;&gt;Open OnDemand&lt;/a&gt;. Dedicating these resources will help to reduce the amount of time users have to wait to launch interactive jobs through OnDemand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about these changes or you experience any issues using OnDemand, &lt;a href=&quot;https://contact.icer.msu.edu/&quot;&gt;please contact us&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2023 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2023/04/03/Intel14-Dedicated-to-Ondemand</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2023/04/03/Intel14-Dedicated-to-Ondemand</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>maintenance</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>SLURM Node Updates on Thursday, March 30th</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;On Thursday, March 30th, at 10:00AM, SLURM clients will be updated to the latest version. This update will bring the node and user components of SLURM to the same version as our SLURM controller and database. Most client commands (e.g. squeue, sbatch, sacct) should work seemlessly through this update. New jobs can be queued as normal and running jobs should not be affected. During these updates, nodes will appear as offline and no new jobs will start. Please note that pending srun/salloc commands may fail to start after this update is complete. If you have a job submitted through srun/salloc that fails after this update, &lt;a href=&quot;https://contact.icer.msu.edu/&quot;&gt;please contact us&lt;/a&gt;. We can boost the priority of your job after resubmission.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about these updates or you experience issues following these updates, &lt;a href=&quot;https://contact.icer.msu.edu/&quot;&gt;please contact us&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2023/03/28/SLURM-Node-Updates</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2023/03/28/SLURM-Node-Updates</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>maintenance</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>MPI Performance Issues Following SLURM Controller Update - Updated</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;UPDATE:&lt;/em&gt; We applied a patch from the software vendor that eliminates the performance issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are currently tracking an issue with MPI job performance following the recent SLURM controller update. We are working with the software vendor and will soon have a patch that fixes these performance issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions or concerns about this issue, &lt;a href=&quot;https://contact.icer.msu.edu/&quot;&gt;please contact us&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2023 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2023/03/23/MPI-Performance</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2023/03/23/MPI-Performance</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>maintenance</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Intel14 nodes to be removed from general queues - Updated</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;UPDATE:&lt;/em&gt; Intel14 nodes have been removed from general queues&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Tuesday, March 21st, intel14 cluster nodes will be removed from the general queues and will no longer be available to run regular jobs. This removal is in preparation to dedicate intel14 hardware to exclusively serve interactive jobs submitted through &lt;a href=&quot;https://ondemand.hpcc.msu.edu/&quot;&gt;OnDemand&lt;/a&gt;. Users who have bought in to the intel14 cluster will still have access to their nodes outside of OnDemand through their regular buy-in accounts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about this change or encounter issues following this change, &lt;a href=&quot;https://contact.icer.msu.edu/&quot;&gt;please contact us&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2023/03/21/Intel14-Removal</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2023/03/21/Intel14-Removal</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>maintenance</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>SLURM Scheduler Update at 5:00PM on 3/16/23 - Updated</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;UPDATE:&lt;/em&gt; The scheduler is back online and functioning normally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;UPDATE:&lt;/em&gt; The scheduler encountered an error following the update and is currently offline. We are working with our software vendor to find a solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Thursday, March 16th, at 5:00PM, the SLURM scheduler will go offline to undergo an upgrade to the latest software release. The scheduler is expected to be offline for less than 30 minutes for this update. During this time, many SLURM client commands will be unavailable, including squeue, sbatch, srun, and salloc. Users will not be able to submit new jobs until the update completes. Running jobs will be unaffected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about this outage or you experience issues following this outage, &lt;a href=&quot;https://contact.icer.msu.edu/&quot;&gt;please contact us&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2023/03/13/SLURM-Controller-Update</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2023/03/13/SLURM-Controller-Update</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>maintenance</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
