<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ICER Announcements Blog</title>
    <description>We'll post information about ICER's system downtimes,  updates, new features, and other information for the ICER user community here.
</description>
    <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//</link>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.icer.msu.edu//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 22:37:51 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 22:37:51 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.2.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>ERROR: Ondemand failing when job is scheduled on a new acm node. 10/12</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Users are reporting intermittent problems with interactive ondemand jobs.  We have tracked the problem down to the jobs failing when they are scheduled on one of the new acm nodes.  We are in the process of isolating the source of the failure. Users will see a “connecting” message&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./images/Connecting.png&quot; alt=&quot;VNC Connecting screenshot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and then the job will fail to start with a screen similar to the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./images/Failed.png&quot; alt=&quot;VNC failure to launch screenshot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can avoid the problem by checking the “Advanced Options” checkbox and then selecting a “Node type” other than “any” (“amd20” is a good choice). This will force the interactive desktop to use one of the working architectures.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2022/10/12/ondemand-acm-error</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2022/10/12/ondemand-acm-error</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>maintenance</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Service availability issues 10/10</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;At about 12:20 PM on October 10th, a bad git merge for our configuration management software caused old configurations to get pushed out to all nodes, which broke a number of services (including the contact forms and job submission on some nodes.) This was reverted by 1:08 PM, but due to caching some nodes may have received this configuration through 2 PM. All nodes and services should be back to normal functionality by 3 PM on October 10th.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 16:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2022/10/10/Service-Availability-Issues</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2022/10/10/Service-Availability-Issues</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>maintenance</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Resolved: Request Tracker and Contact Forms outage on 10/11</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Update 10/11 8 AM: Maintenance on RT has completed. Please let us know if you have any issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The HPCC’s main ticketing system &lt;a href=&quot;https://rt.hpcc.msu.edu&quot;&gt;https://rt.hpcc.msu.edu&lt;/a&gt; and the contact forms &lt;a href=&quot;https://contact.icer.msu.edu&quot;&gt;https://contact.icer.msu.edu&lt;/a&gt; will be unavailable from 4 AM to 9 AM for a major software update. During this time users can contact ICER via the ICER-public MSU Teams instance or via phone for critical issues: &lt;a href=&quot;https://icer.msu.edu/contact&quot;&gt;https://icer.msu.edu/contact&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Update 10/10: We have extended the maintenance window from 4 AM to 9 PM.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2022 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2022/10/07/RequestTracker-Upgrade</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2022/10/07/RequestTracker-Upgrade</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>maintenance</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>HPCC Scratch filesystem issues - Resolved</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The HPCC scratch filesystem is currently experiencing an issue. Users may have seen issues as early as 7:30 AM this morning.  We are working to identify the cause and correct the issue and will post updates here as they become available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update&lt;/strong&gt;: 10:45 AM. We have identified a hardware failure and are working with IBM to diagnose and repair.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update&lt;/strong&gt;: 11:50 AM. Scratch filesystem access has been restored, however we are still operating in a degraded state and some interruption of service is possible.  We continue to work on resolving the issue and restoring services completetly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update&lt;/strong&gt;: As of 12:30 PM all services have been restored. &lt;a href=&quot;https://contact.icer.msu.edu&quot;&gt;Please let us know if you have any issues.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 11:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/update/2022/10/04/scratch-issues</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/update/2022/10/04/scratch-issues</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>maintenance</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Password logins to the rsync gateway will be disabled on 10/12/22</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Beginning on &lt;strong&gt;October 12, 2022&lt;/strong&gt;, ICER will be disabling password authentication to the rsync gateway (rsync.hpcc.msu.edu). In order to improve our operational security, SSH key based authentication will be the only supported method to access the rsync gateway (rsync.hpcc.msu.edu).  Access to login gateways (hpcc.msu.edu) will be unaffected by this change.  For additional information on using SSH key based authentication, please review the documentation at https://docs.icer.msu.edu/SSH_Key-Based_Authentication/.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2022 17:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2022/09/27/Password-logins-to-rsync-gateway-disabled</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2022/09/27/Password-logins-to-rsync-gateway-disabled</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>maintenance</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>New Scratch gs21 availability and gs18/ls15 retirement - UPDATED</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We are excited to announce the general release of our new gs21 scratch system, now available at /mnt/gs21/scratch on all user systems, including gateways, development nodes, and the compute cluster. The new scratch system provides 3 PB of space for researchers and allows us to continue to maintain 50 TB quotas for our growing community. The new system also includes 200 TB of high-speed flash. You may begin to utilize the new scratch system immediately. Please read on for more information about the transition to this space.
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On July 1st, /mnt/scratch and the $SCRATCH variable will be updated to point to the new gs21 space. On July 15th, ls15 and gs18 will be marked read-only, and will be removed from service on July 31st. Please update your scripts or programs that explicitly use gs18 and ls15 to use gs21. If you have a large quantity of data (&amp;gt;10 TB) to move from the old systems to the new, please contact us and we can help you use tools to transfer the data quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to the high utilization of gs18 and the age of ls15 and gs18, we are encouraging users to begin migrating to gs21 at their earliest convenience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;update&lt;/strong&gt;: Due to a number of circumstances, the $SCRATCH environment variable will be updated on Friday, July 15, 2022. ls15/gs18 will be marked read-only on July 22, 2022 and removed from service on July 31, 2022.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update 8/31&lt;/strong&gt;: gs18 and ls15 were removed from the compute nodes on July 31st. The systems will be taken completely offline on September 15th. Please contact us if you need help retrieving data from these systems.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2022 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/update/2022/08/31/new-gs21-scratch</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/update/2022/08/31/new-gs21-scratch</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>maintenance</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>File Transfer Service Network Migration - Resolved</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;UPDATE:&lt;/em&gt; The rsync service (rsync.hpcc.msu.edu) is available (8-31). A reminder that the rsync service node should only be used for file transfers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;UPDATE:&lt;/em&gt; The Globus Online endpoint (msu#hpcc) is available (8-31)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about this outage or you experience issues following this outage, &lt;a href=&quot;https://contact.icer.msu.edu/&quot;&gt;please contact us&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2022 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//maintenance/outage/2022/08/31/File-Transfer-Service-Migration</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//maintenance/outage/2022/08/31/File-Transfer-Service-Migration</guid>
        
        
        <category>maintenance</category>
        
        <category>outage</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Brief Scheduler Outage at 8:00PM 8/18/22 - UPDATED</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;On Thursday, August 18th, at 8:00PM, there will be a brief interruption in scheduling as we push an update to our SLURM configration. We expect this outage to last roughly 30 minutes. During this outage, SLURM client commands will be unavailable (e.g. srun/salloc/sbatch). Running jobs should not be affected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about this outage or you experience issues following this outage, &lt;a href=&quot;https://contact.icer.msu.edu/&quot;&gt;please contact us&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UPDATE&lt;/strong&gt;: Due to unforseen complications with the configuration update, many running jobs were requeued. Jobs requeued due to this issue have been moved to the top of the queue. We apologize for any inconvenience.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2022 14:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2022/08/17/SLURM-Configuration-update</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2022/08/17/SLURM-Configuration-update</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>maintenance</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Boosts to Job Priority Being Offered to Users Affected by Scheduler Issue</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Many running jobs were cancelled due to unforseen complications with yesterdays SLURM configuration update. We are reaching out to affected users and offering boosts to job priority to make up for any lost productivity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions, &lt;a href=&quot;https://contact.icer.msu.edu/&quot;&gt;please contact us&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 12:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2022/08/04/Priority-Boosts</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2022/08/04/Priority-Boosts</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>maintenance</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Brief Scheduler Outage at 8:00PM 8/3/22 - UPDATED</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;On Wednesday, August 3rd, at 8:00PM, there will be a brief interruption in scheduling as we push an update to our SLURM configration. We expect this outage to last roughly 30 minutes. During this outage, SLURM client commands will be unavailable (e.g. srun/salloc/sbatch). Running jobs should not be affected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about this outage or you experience issues following this outage, &lt;a href=&quot;https://contact.icer.msu.edu/&quot;&gt;please contact us&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UPDATE&lt;/strong&gt;: Due to unforseen complications with the configuration update, many running jobs were cancelled. We apologize for any inconvenience.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 17:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2022/08/01/SLURM-Configuration-update</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2022/08/01/SLURM-Configuration-update</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>maintenance</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
