<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ICER Announcements Blog</title>
    <description>We'll post information about ICER's system downtimes,  updates, new features, and other information for the ICER user community here.
</description>
    <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//</link>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.icer.msu.edu//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 12:25:23 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 12:25:23 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.2.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Compute Operating system upgrades</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;On 17 June, 2024 the primary operating system on HPCC resources will change from Centos 7 to Ubuntu 22.04.
Please review our documentation (https://docs.icer.msu.edu/OS_Upgrade/)                &lt;br /&gt;
for details and currently available Ubuntu development nodes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 08:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/2024/06/17/OS_Upgrade</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/2024/06/17/OS_Upgrade</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Samba connectivity issues</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;UPDATE 3:45pm 5/16/24 Samba file sharing is now back online. Please submit a ticket at https://contact.icer.msu.edu/contact if you continue to experience issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Samba file sharing is currently not available as part of the filesystem outages this week. We are working to restore functionality and will update this post once it is restored.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2024 15:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/2024/05/16/Samba-connectivity</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/2024/05/16/Samba-connectivity</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Home filesystem issues - update</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;At approximately 6:15PM on 5/13/2024, users began reporting issues accessing their home directory on HPCC. We are aware of the issue and are working with our vendors to address it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Update: 11:55 PM, 5/13. We are currently on a call with the vendor team to diagonse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Update: 2:30 AM, 5/14. Shortly after the cutover to new hardware, there was a bug that took the home file system offline. The vendor is examining diagnostic data to determine possible solutions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Update: 9:00 AM, 5/14. Home directories are still unavailable.  Vendor continues to work on a solution.  No ETA yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Update: 3 PM 5/14. The vendor has identified problems that may have caused this outage. The system is recovering the file system but it requires a scan of all the data on the system. Our expected ETA for recovery is currently mid-afternoon, 5/15.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Update: 9 PM 5/14. The scan is about 22% complete.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Update: 10:45 AM 5/15. The file system scan has completed and has successfully mounted the file system on the storage servers. HPCC staff is work on restoring access to gateway and compute nodes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Update: 5:15 PM 5/15. The file system is online without data loss.  Most nodes now have the filesystem properly mounted and ready for jobs.  We will continue to monitor and fix problems as we detect them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 03:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/2024/05/13/HomeDirectory_issues</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/2024/05/13/HomeDirectory_issues</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Home filesystem issues causing login problems</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;At approximately 11:10 AM on 5/10/2024 we experienced a transient outage while conducting upgrades and hardware refresh of our Home filesystem.  This outage may have caused login issues or stale filemounts.  Services were restored after approximately 15 minutes and home directories should be available again.  If you countinue to experience issues with your home directory, &lt;a href=&quot;https://contact.icer.msu.edu/&quot;&gt;please contact us&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 03:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/2024/05/10/Filesystem_issues</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/2024/05/10/Filesystem_issues</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>System Reboots Thursday May 9</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;On Thursday May 9 the following systems will be rebooted from 10-12am:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;gateway-[00-04]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;globus-02&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;rdpgw&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;openondemand&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will briefly impact login services, Globus, and Openondemand.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 07:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/2024/05/06/System-Reboots</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/2024/05/06/System-Reboots</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Home filesystem issue UPDATED 5/3/2024 5:00PM</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;UPDATE (5/3/2024 5:00 pm) - The issue has been resolved and all services should be available. If you encounter any additional issues, &lt;a href=&quot;https://contact.icer.msu.edu/&quot;&gt;please contact us&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At approximately 4:30PM on 5/3/24, we started having an issue with our home filesystem that is impacting operations related to home directories, including logins and OnDemand. This appears to be a network issue that we are investigating and will post an update once we have additional information.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 07:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/2024/05/03/Home-Directory-Problems</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/2024/05/03/Home-Directory-Problems</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Home filesystem issue causing login problems - UPDATED 5/2/2024 12:30 pm</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;UPDATE (5/2/2024 12:30 pm) - File system and connectivity issues have been resolved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UPDATE (4/25/2024 3:40 pm) - We are still receiving reports of connection and storage issues. Samba authentication is also currently down. We are working to resolve these issues. If you encounter any additional issues, &lt;a href=&quot;https://contact.icer.msu.edu/&quot;&gt;please contact us&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UPDATE (4/25/2024 1:00 pm) - We are still receiving reports of connection and storage issues, specifically localized around dev-amd20. We are working to resolve the issue. Please use different development nodes in the meantime.  If you encounter any additional issues, &lt;a href=&quot;https://contact.icer.msu.edu/&quot;&gt;please contact us&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UPDATE (4/25/2024 11:45 am) - We have resolved slowdown issues related to the file system on the cluster. If you encounter any additional issues, &lt;a href=&quot;https://contact.icer.msu.edu/&quot;&gt;please contact us&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UPDATE (4/25/2024 8:45 am) - We have received reports of slow responses to commands on the system and are investigating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UPDATE (4/24/2024 4:05 pm) - During upgrade and hardware refresh of our home filesystem, an unforseen error caused an outage.  The problem node has been removed from service and all services should be available.  If you encounter any additional issues, &lt;a href=&quot;https://contact.icer.msu.edu/&quot;&gt;please contact us&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At approximately 3:00 pm on 4/24/24 we started having an issue with our home filesystem that is impacting logins.  We are investigating and will post an update once we have additional information.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 15:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/2024/05/02/Filesystem_issues</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/2024/05/02/Filesystem_issues</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Scheduler Reboot at 10:00AM on 3/19/24</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;At 10:00AM on Tuesday, March 19th, the SLURM scheduling server will go offline for a reboot. This reboot is necessary to apply updates to the underlying hardware that hosts the scheduler. The scheduler is expected to be offline for roughly 15 minutes. During this time, jobs may not be submitted and scheduler specific client commands will not work (e.g. squeue, sbatch, etc). Running jobs will not be affected. If you have any questions about this outage, &lt;a href=&quot;https://contact.icer.msu.edu/&quot;&gt;please contact us&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 12:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/2024/03/18/SLURM_Controller_Reboot</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/2024/03/18/SLURM_Controller_Reboot</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Scheduler Reboot at 10:00AM on 3/18/24</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;At 10:00AM on Monday, March 18th, the SLURM scheduling server will go offline for a reboot. This reboot is necessary to apply updates to the underlying hardware that hosts the scheduler. The scheduler is expected to be offline for roughly 15 minutes. During this time, jobs may not be submitted and scheduler specific client commands will not work (e.g. squeue, sbatch, etc). Running jobs will not be affected. If you have any questions about this outage, &lt;a href=&quot;https://contact.icer.msu.edu/&quot;&gt;please contact us&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 12:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/2024/03/15/SLURM_Controller_Reboot</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/2024/03/15/SLURM_Controller_Reboot</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Scratch space not acccessible via OnDemand</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;UPDATE (3/1/2024) - Access to scratch via OnDemand has been restored&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are aware of an issue where users are unable to access their scratch space via OnDeamnd. We are currently looking into the issue and will post further updates here. Scratch space is still accessible through SSH&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/2024/03/01/Scratch_OnDemand_Problem</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/2024/03/01/Scratch_OnDemand_Problem</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
