<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>HPCC Service Status</title>
    <description>We'll post information about ICER's system downtimes,  updates, new features, and other information for the ICER user community here.
</description>
    <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//</link>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.icer.msu.edu//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2024 19:33:19 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2024 19:33:19 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.2.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>File System Performance Update</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As we continue our efforts to improve the HPCC file systems and user experience, we are taking additional steps to ensure the home and research file systems have fully recovered from the outage that occurred this past May and proceed with the migration to the new home directory and research hardware.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beginning on August 14, additional steps will be taken that require us to intermittently stop disaster recovery replication. This means that if you delete or modify files in home and research spaces while disaster recovery replication is disabled, we may not be able to recover changes made while replication is disabled. Home file system performance may also be impacted throughout this time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because disaster recovery replication will be intermittent, you can choose to copy your data into your scratch space if you would like to maintain additional, temporary copies. While the scratch data is deleted every 45 days, we plan to have disaster recovery backups running normally before then. The scratch space will not be affected by the home system migration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This blog post will continue to be updated until the filesystem upgrade project is completed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 06:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2024/08/13/File-System-Performance-Update</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2024/08/13/File-System-Performance-Update</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>maintenance</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Filesystem Slowdown and User Creation Pause - RESOLVED</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;UPDATE 8/13/2024: The recovery processes have finished running, and Home filesystem performance has now returned to normal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The HPCC’s filesystem is experiencing a slow down due to ongoing recovery efforts for the Home filesystem outage back in May. System administrators are aware of the issue and actively working on its resolution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UPDATE: The first publishing of this post incorrectly indicated that the creation of new user accounts had been paused. Account creation is unaffected by recovery efforts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UPDATE: Monday 8/12/2024 - The recovery processes are continuing to run on the Home filesystem and the slow down will continue to occur while these processes run. Our team will provide another update on Wednesday, August 14, 2024.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/bug/2024/08/09/Filesystem-slowdown</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/bug/2024/08/09/Filesystem-slowdown</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>bug</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>August 6, 2024: HPCC Scheduled Downtime and Transition of Remaining CentOS Nodes (Completed 8/6/2024)</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Updates:
05:00PM - Upgrades are complete and in the processes of moving the system to production.  This process takes about 30 minutes.  HPCC should be available by 5:30PM or shortly after.  Home and Research filesystem is little slow while snapshots catch up.  Those will clear later this evening.  If you notice problems, &lt;a href=&quot;https://contact.icer.msu.edu&quot;&gt;contact us&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;03:30PM - Going through checklist before opening to all users.  Not much longer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10:00AM - Network updates completed.  Node upgrades and filesystem repairs moving forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The HPCC will be unavailable on Tuesday, August 6th for our regularly scheduled maintenance. No jobs will run during this time. Jobs that will not be completed before August 6th will not begin until after maintenance is complete. For example, if you submit a four day job three days before the maintenance outage, your job will be postponed and will not begin to run until after maintenance is completed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this time, ICER will also be upgrading all remaining nodes on the old operating system to the new operating system. After this date, nodes running the old operating system will no longer be available. If you haven’t already, please follow &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.icer.msu.edu/Migrating_to_the_New_Operating_System/&quot;&gt;the steps to transition to the new operating system&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information on what happens during downtime, see &lt;a href=&quot;https://icer.msu.edu/about/announcements/what-purpose-scheduled-downtimes-hpcc&quot;&gt;our explanation here&lt;/a&gt;. If you have any questions, please &lt;a href=&quot;https://contact.icer.msu.edu&quot;&gt;contact us&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2024/08/06/Scheduled-Maintenance</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2024/08/06/Scheduled-Maintenance</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>maintenance</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>RESOLVED 7/31/24 Scavenger Queue jobs not starting</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The scavenger queue is operating normally now that the buyin node OS transition has been completed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As of July 19th, jobs assigned to the Scavenger Queue are not starting. Please resubmit these jobs to the main queue in the meantime while ICER staff investigate the issue.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2024 18:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/bug/2024/07/22/Scavenger-Queue-Issues</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/bug/2024/07/22/Scavenger-Queue-Issues</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>bug</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Data machine nodes not showing up in scontrol - UPDATED</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;On July 12th, it was discovered that the data machine nodes are not properly responding to diagnostic commands. However, these nodes are still available and scheduling jobs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example commands like&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;checknode nal-004
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;or&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;scontrol show node nal-004
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;will show output like&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Node nal-004 not found
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the moment, this appears to be limited to nodes in the data machine. We are investigating and will update with any resolution or further issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UPDATE:&lt;/strong&gt; (Monday, July 15, 2:30PM) This issue still persists, and ICER sysadmins are continuing to diagnose. We believe that this may also affect some buy-in nodes outside of the Data Machine. As a workaround, users can use the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;-a&lt;/code&gt; option with &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;scontrol&lt;/code&gt;, like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-bash highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;scontrol show node nal-004 &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;-a&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2024 20:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/bug/2024/07/12/Minor-data-machine-issue</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/bug/2024/07/12/Minor-data-machine-issue</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>bug</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Rebuilding default OpenMPI, may cause login issues - RESOLVED</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;On July 11th, 2024 from 5:30-6:00PM Michigan time, we will be rebuilding the default OpenMPI module, &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;OpenMPI/4.1.5-GCC-12.3.0&lt;/code&gt;. This will result in errors from the module system when logging in, as the module needs to be deleted to be rebuilt. This will &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; affect running jobs, and will be isolated to development nodes only. The rebuild should be complete by 6:00PM at which time this blog post will be updated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RESOLVED&lt;/strong&gt;: This has been completed and the rebuilt version of OpenMPI is now available&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 15:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2024/07/11/MPI-Rebuild</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2024/07/11/MPI-Rebuild</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>maintenance</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Update details about current filesystem and OnDemand issues</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;OnDemand:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; OnDemand is periodically losing connection to our gateway nodes. This makes home and scratch unavailable. We are still investigating the cause. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Home directories&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: The home file system underwent diagnostics from 6/24-6/28. This caused slowdowns for logging in and using the HPCC. We have restarted our backup process after the scan ended 6/28 evening and users may see pauses as the file system catches up. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;NewOS:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; We upgraded our operating system to Ubuntu 22.04 in mid June. This included a reinstallation of all software modules. Please read our documentation &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.icer.msu.edu/OS_Upgrade/&quot;&gt;here &lt;/a&gt;for more details about the upgrade, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://contact.icer.msu.edu/contact&quot;&gt;contact us&lt;/a&gt; if you are having issues not covered by this documentation. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Please click the title of this post for more detailed information and our planned timeline.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Updated: 7/10&lt;/strong&gt; at the end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-problem&quot;&gt;The Problem:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although many jobs are still running successfully, the current system instabilities are an unfortunate confluence of multiple issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Home Directories&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: First and foremost are instabilities in our home directory filesystem.   This instability is causing intermittent access to the HPCC via SSH and OnDemand. Home is experiencing performance issues for two reasons:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;After the failure of the migration process to our new file system in May, there were a small number of files that have prevented us from resuming the migration to the new hardware. After multiple discussions with the vendor, IBM provided a process to identify the failed files. We started that process last week which caused a significant performance penalty and took significantly longer than expected to run. It started Wednesday and ended late Friday. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;To start the file check process, offsite backup replications needed to be disabled. When backups are restarted, the system needs to take a snapshot of every fileset on the system and scan for changes. Each snapshot requires the entire system to pause (for up to a minute) to ensure that the filesystem is consistent across all 1,000 nodes. We have restarted the replication after the scan failed Friday evening and users may continue to see pauses as the file system catches up. The vendor anticipates that these pauses may continue for a couple of days but we acknowledge that this is just a rough estimation and may be unreliable given our previous estimates.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our immediate goal is to fix the issues with the file migration and move accounts to the new file system. This will require that we work with the vendor to analyze the data we got to try and identify the underlying problem.  It is possible we may need to run another system diagnostic but we want to avoid the problems we had last week and are working with the vendor to identify ways to make it less painful if we didn`t catch the problem this first time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;OnDemand&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: The OnDemand server is periodically experiencing a communication error between it and the rest of the gateway nodes. When this happens, home or the scratch system becomes temporarily unavailable in OnDemand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These communication instabilities may also cause a user’s OnDemand session to be improperly disconnected. These disconnects can cause “stale” cookies and result in local browser issues that require users to clear out OnDemand browser cookies before being able to connect to OnDemand.  The cookie issue and the communication issues can result in  similar error messages. The exact kind of error will also vary based on the user`s computer and version of browser they are running. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Users may need to clear their browser cookies when trying to connect&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although we have been able to eliminate many potential sources of the problem from consideration, it is currently not clear what is the root cause of the communication errors between ondemand and the gateway servers.  ICER has some short term “fixes” that require our manual intervention but we are still debugging to identify a long term solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;New OS&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Last week we also started a major migration of compute nodes to the new Ubuntu Operating System.  This is a long overdue upgrade and will significantly improve the long term stability and reliability of the system.  Unfortunately, as with any major upgrade, there is a long list of issues and bugs that will need to be addressed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Although the new OS is not the cause of the home directory filesystem issues, its changeover has complicated the debugging process.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;timeline&quot;&gt;Timeline:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Right now&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (Week of July 1st 2024), the system should finish up its resynchronization process in the next few days which should result in a much more stable system in the short term.  We will continuously monitor and watch the system while we work with the vendor to review the diagnostic data and debug the problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is unclear how long it will take the vendor to get back to us with a fix to their file system migration process.  If the vendor is able to find a solution to the home directory issues this week, we would likely try to avoid trying another “live” migration and thus schedule some migration downtime which would not happen for at least another 2 weeks in order to empty out the scheduler.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the vendor is unable to identify the problem they may be asking us to rerun the system diagnostic again.  If this is required we are trying to identify ways to ensure that the system will remain stable during the diagnosis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;August&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: water cooling is being added to the MSU Data Center to allow for more high power compute systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fall&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: a new CPU and GPU cluster will be installed to connect to the new water cooling system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Spring Semester&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Installation of a new high speed file system optimized for lots of small files. This new system will help us optimize workflows based on file types and significantly improve performance across all of our file systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;workarounds&quot;&gt;Workarounds:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We realize it can be extremely frustrating debugging problems on an unstable system.  It is often difficult to know if the problem is short term, long term, a known system issue, something you need to report or something wrong with your own workflow.  Please contact us if you need help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although we have a number of system monitors and tests, they do not always pick up the scale of the problems.  We encourage everyone to submit a ticket when they are experiencing a problem (&lt;a href=&quot;http://contact.icer.msu.edu&quot;&gt;http://contact.icer.msu.edu&lt;/a&gt;) to ensure we know that there are issues and we may be able to suggest a temporary solution or workaround.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ICER Research Consultants have been working with individuals and groups to identify ways to work around all of these issues.  These fixes are often workflow dependent. Please reach out to us if you would like help with your workflow. When possible we will try to document the most common of these workarounds in lab notebooks on our documentation page:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lab Notebook: &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.icer.msu.edu/2024-07-01_LabNotebook_OnDemandWorkaround/&quot;&gt;https://docs.icer.msu.edu/2024-07-01_LabNotebook_OnDemandWorkaround/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;updates&quot;&gt;Updates:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7/10/24&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main OnDemand issue has been resolved last week. We have seen some “Proxy Connection Errrors” when Slurm is under significant load; reloading should resolve the issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The home file system has been stable. We are waiting on the vendor to analyze the logs to determine to resolve the issue with the migration process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The NewOS migration is continuing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 15:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/2024/07/01/Details-About-Current-Issues</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/2024/07/01/Details-About-Current-Issues</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Current system issues</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We are aware of two issues affected the system at this time: slow response to commands/slow login, and OnDemand scratch space missing. 
The system slowdowns are caused by diagnostics on the home filesystem as part of our upgrade to a new home filesystem.
We do not currently have an estimate for when these diagnostics will complete. 
The OnDemand scratch space connection is also being diagnosed and addressed with our storage vendor.
Please check back for updates as we have them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 12:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/2024/06/27/Current-Issues</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/2024/06/27/Current-Issues</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Home filesystem issues affecting OnDemand</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;OnDemand functionality has been partially recovered. Users should be able to log in, connect, and access their home and research spaces, as well as interactive app sessions. Scratch remains unavailable at this time. Please report access issues at https://contact.icer.msu.edu/contact&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At approximately 2:00 PM on 6/24/2024 we started experiencing an outage with the Home filesystem.  This outage primarily affects OnDemand, but may be apparent on other nodes as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These issues may result in your home directory not appearing or receiving errors like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;#&amp;lt;Errno::EEXIST: File exists @ dir_s_mkdir - /mnt/home&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may also see login issues or stale filemounts.  ICER is working on resolving this problem.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2024 15:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/2024/06/24/Home_filesystem_issues_affecting_OnDemand</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/2024/06/24/Home_filesystem_issues_affecting_OnDemand</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Home filesystem issues affecting OnDemand - Resolved</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;At approximately 12:00 PM on 6/17/2024 we started experiencing an outage with the Home filesystem.  This outage primarily affects OnDemand, but may be apparent on other nodes as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These issues may result in your home directory not appearing or receiving errors like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;#&amp;lt;Errno::EEXIST: File exists @ dir_s_mkdir - /mnt/home&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may also see login issues or stale filemounts.  ICER is working on resolving this problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Update 6/17, 2:00PM: The home filesystem is back online and recovering on some nodes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Update 6/18, 2:30PM: The filesystem issues are still persisting, primarily on OnDemand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Update 6/19, 9:00AM: The filesystem issues on OnDemand have been resolved. Please &lt;a href=&quot;https://contact.icer.msu.edu&quot;&gt;submit a ticket&lt;/a&gt; if you are still having any problems.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 15:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/2024/06/17/Filesystem_issues</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/2024/06/17/Filesystem_issues</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
