<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>HPCC Service Status</title>
    <description>We'll post information about ICER's system downtimes,  updates, new features, and other information for the ICER user community here.
</description>
    <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//</link>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.icer.msu.edu//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 14:07:39 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 14:07:39 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.2.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Network Issues</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;UPDATE: External connectivity has been restored to rsync and Globus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UPDATE: All failed network hardware that caused yesterday’s outage has been replaced. Rsync and globus access from non-Internet2 sites are not available as of 7 PM, 1/20/2026, due to a routing configuration change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During network maintenance, a core Ethernet switch had a hardware failure at 2:01 PM. During this window, access to all external HPCC services (gateways, dev nodes, OOD, Contact) were interrupted. Service was restored by 2:20. ICER and ITS have identified failed hardware and working to replace the failed component tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you notice additional problems, &lt;a href=&quot;https://contact.icer.msu.edu/&quot;&gt;please contact us&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//maintenance/2026/01/20/Network_issues</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//maintenance/2026/01/20/Network_issues</guid>
        
        <category>resolved</category>
        
        
        <category>maintenance</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Slurm Job ID Reset</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Slurm job IDs have reset back to 1 after surpassing the maxumum job ID of 67,043,328. This has occurred every few years and is expected behavior that should not have any adverse impact on jobs. If you have any quesions about this reset, please &lt;a href=&quot;https://contact.icer.msu.edu&quot;&gt;contact us&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/2026/01/13/Job-IDs-Reset</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/2026/01/13/Job-IDs-Reset</guid>
        
        <category>resolved</category>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>CPU/GPU Hour Limits Reset</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Happy New Year! Per &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.icer.msu.edu/job_policies/&quot;&gt;ICER policy&lt;/a&gt; , users who are not associated with a buy-in account are limited to 500,000 CPU and 10,000 GPU hours per year. With the new year comes new beginnings as these CPU/GPU hour limits are reset. If you have any questions about this reset, please &lt;a href=&quot;https://contact.icer.msu.edu&quot;&gt;contact us&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/2026/01/05/CPU-GPU-Hours-Reset</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/2026/01/05/CPU-GPU-Hours-Reset</guid>
        
        <category>resolved</category>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Winter Break Limited Coverage</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;There will be limited coverage while MSU observes winter break from December 20, 2025 through January 5, 2026.  The system will continue to run jobs and monitored for emergency issues.  Tickets will be sorted by priority on January 5 when our team returns to work after the holiday break.
If you have any questions, &lt;a href=&quot;https://contact.icer.msu.edu/&quot;&gt;please contact us&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/2025/12/16/Winter-Hours</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/2025/12/16/Winter-Hours</guid>
        
        <category>resolved</category>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Research Space File System Issues</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;On Saturday, 12/06/2025, a brief outage occurred on the file system hosting research spaces. This outage reoccurred on Monday, 12/08/2025. To mitigate impacts to our users and their running jobs, we disabled some features on the file system at that time. Beginning Thursday, 12/11/2025, we began reenabling all file system features. Due to the work on Thursday, 12/11, periodic slowdowns and pauses on the file system have been reported. We are aware of this issue, and are actively working with our vendor to resolve these slowdowns and pauses as quickly as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 17:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//maintenance/2025/12/15/research-filesystem-issues</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//maintenance/2025/12/15/research-filesystem-issues</guid>
        
        <category>open</category>
        
        
        <category>maintenance</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Slurm Database Outage at 10:00AM on 12/15/25 - RESOLVED</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;RESOLVED: At 11:30AM, the Slurm database upgrade completed without issue. The database is now back online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Monday, December 15th, at 10:00AM, the SLURM database will go offline to undergo a major Slurm version update. The database is expected to be offline through the upcoming downtime. During this outage, the sacct client command will be unavailable for querying job information and job queue time estimations will not be updated. Other client commands (e.g. squeue, srun, sbatch, salloc) will continue to work as expected. Jobs may still be submitted and will start normally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about this outage or you experience issues following this outage, &lt;a href=&quot;https://contact.icer.msu.edu/&quot;&gt;please contact us&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//maintenance/2025/12/12/SLURM-Database-Update</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//maintenance/2025/12/12/SLURM-Database-Update</guid>
        
        <category>resolved</category>
        
        
        <category>maintenance</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Login Problems - RESOLVED</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;RESOLVED: 11:00AM - The issue has been identified and resolved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ICER is experiencing filesystem problems on login nodes, including OnDemand.  You will experience a login that hangs with no prompt.  We are working on it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//maintenance/2025/12/08/Login_Problems</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//maintenance/2025/12/08/Login_Problems</guid>
        
        <category>resolved</category>
        
        
        <category>maintenance</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>AMD24 Downtime to Fix Small Leak in Liquid Cooling Pipe - RESOLVED 12/10/2025</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;UPDATE 12/10/2025 - Repairs were completed earlier than expected.  Everything is back online.  Please contact us if you notice anything wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UPDATE 12/5/2025 - Our water cooling vendor scheduled the repairs for Wed, 12/10/2025, first thing in the morning.  Jobs on AMD24 will be killed shortly after the repairs start.  The repairs will take 14-18 hours, during which AMD24 will remain offline. We will continue to monitor the cooling systems closely until then.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the repair of ICER’s liquid cooling pumps, we detected a small leak in the piping. This leak does not endanger ICER’s equipment, but we need to do an emergency repair that requires us to take the AMD24 cluster down for approximately 14 to 18 hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the repair parts are currently in transit, we do not yet have specific details about the maintenance. We have been told it will be early next week. AMD24 will need to be shut down for one to two days. We will update this blog with specifics as we gather more information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions, please contact us using our &lt;a href=&quot;https://contact.icer.msu.edu/&quot;&gt;contact form&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//maintenance/2025/12/03/Water_Cooling_Warranty_Repairs</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//maintenance/2025/12/03/Water_Cooling_Warranty_Repairs</guid>
        
        <category>resolved</category>
        
        
        <category>maintenance</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Water Cooling Repairs for AMD24 - Final Steps, Again - RESOLVED</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;UPDATE 11/24/2025 - IPF completed the switchover and the temporary chiller is no longer being used.
&lt;!--more--&gt;
UPDATE 11/20/2025 - IPF is planning on completing this step between 8am-11am on Friday Nov 21.  This time frame is much smaller now and we do not expect the water cooling temps to exceed any limits and not scheduling any downtime.  We will monitor it closely and will only kill jobs and shut down machines as a last resort if needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UPDATE 11/18/2025 - Waiting on update from IPF for a new completion date.  Hope to know more later today.  Will likely be delayed a few days.  We will give as much notice as possible, but may have to kill jobs to accommodate revised timelines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UPDATE 11/17/2025 - IPF ran into problems and are not ready to change the diverter on Nov 18.  We are canceling the maintenance reservation and jobs will continue like normal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final step needed to repair our water pumps from the 7/9 failure will occur Tues, Nov 18 at 7am and expected to be completed by 5pm.  The primary loop will be diverted back to the main unit.  During that time our main water cooling will be down for the AMD24 and Intel18 clusters.  No jobs will run on the AMD24 and Intel18 clusters during this time.  Jobs that will not be completed before November 18th will not begin until after maintenance is complete. For example, if you submit a four day job three days before the maintenance outage, your job will be postponed and will not begin to run until after maintenance is completed.&lt;br /&gt;
If you have any questions, &lt;a href=&quot;https://contact.icer.msu.edu/&quot;&gt;please contact us&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2025/11/11/Water-Repairs-Final-Step</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2025/11/11/Water-Repairs-Final-Step</guid>
        
        <category>resolved</category>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>maintenance</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Update to FairShare Priority Calculation</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We have have updated scheduler parameters that determine how users’ recent cluster usage affects their FairShare priority factor. Previously, memory usage was weighted higher than CPU usage and GPU usage was not considered. Now, CPU, memory, and GPU usage are all considered in the calculation of FairShare priority and weighted in proportion to the overall availability of those resources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More information about this change can be found in our &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.icer.msu.edu/How_Jobs_are_Scheduled/&quot;&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about this change, please &lt;a href=&quot;https://contact.icer.msu.edu/contact&quot;&gt;contact us&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/2025/11/10/Update-to-FairShare</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/2025/11/10/Update-to-FairShare</guid>
        
        <category>open</category>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
