<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ICER Announcements Blog</title>
    <description>We'll post information about ICER's system downtimes,  updates, new features, and other information for the ICER user community here.
</description>
    <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//</link>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.icer.msu.edu//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 15:05:46 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 15:05:46 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.2.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Performance problem on home system - resolved</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;UPDATE: 
8/31/2023
The cause of the system slowdowns was identified on 8/29/2023 as jobs saturating the storage I/O.  Please follow the &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.icer.msu.edu/2023-08-30_LabNotebook_SlowdownIncidentReport/&quot;&gt;lab notebook&lt;/a&gt; for details and best practices to prevent this from happening again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UPDATE: The performance issues with the home directory system have been resolved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UPDATE: We’ve identified a likely problem and are working with the storage vendor to confirm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are currently seeing performance issues with the home directory system due to possible hardware issues. An update will be posted once remediation steps have been identified.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/2023/08/31/Home-Directory-Performance-Issues-Updated</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/2023/08/31/Home-Directory-Performance-Issues-Updated</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Globus Restored to Service - 8/16/2023</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;8/16/2023:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Globus has been restored to service.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/2023/08/16/Globus-Restored</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/2023/08/16/Globus-Restored</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>HPCC Scheduled Downtime - UPDATED 8/15/2023</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;UPDATE (8/15/2023):
All scheduled updates are completed for the 8/15/2023 summer maintenance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Changes include updates to all gateways, increased network resiliency (addressing the source of our recent outages), reinstalling some dev nodes, upgrading backend servers, adding reliability and performance for /opt/software, and a major Open OnDemand upgrade (version  2 -&amp;gt; version 3).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are still resolving a globus error.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our tests look good, however &lt;a href=&quot;https://contact.icer.msu.edu/&quot;&gt;please contact us&lt;/a&gt; if you encounter any errors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UPDATE (8/7/2023): Due to unforeseen circumstances, the ICER maintenance and downtime scheduled for Tuesday, August 8th will not proceed as planned. The maintenance window and downtime are rescheduled for Tuesday, August 15, 2023. No jobs will run during the August 15 maintenance window.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any jobs scheduled to complete between now and end of day August 14th will continue to run as scheduled.  Jobs that will not be completed before August 15th will not begin until after maintenance is complete. For example, if you submit a four day job three days before the maintenance outage, your job will be postponed and will not begin to run until after maintenance is completed. If you have any questions, &lt;a href=&quot;https://contact.icer.msu.edu/&quot;&gt;please contact us&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2023 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/2023/08/15/Summer-Maintenance</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/2023/08/15/Summer-Maintenance</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>HPCC Connectivity Issues</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Update:
Network problems in the data center were fixed by 3pm.&lt;br /&gt;
Stability with home directories and gateways were restored by 5:30pm.
File a ticket if you notice any other issues.  We will continue to monitor closely this evening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are experiencing an issue with logging in to the gateways, on-demand, and our webservices.  We’re in the process of tracking down this issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will update this post when we have more information.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 14:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/outage/2023/08/02/HPCC-connectivity-issues</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/outage/2023/08/02/HPCC-connectivity-issues</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>outage</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Intermittent HPCC Performance Issues</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We are experiencing sporadic episodes of slowness with logging in to the gateways and/or interactive work on the development nodes.  We’re in the process of tracking down this issue.  If you are experiencing this issue and/or have any other comments or questions, please feel free to file a ticket with us here: https://contact.icer.msu.edu/contact&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will update this post when we have more information.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 13:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/outage/2023/07/26/intermittent-performance-issues</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/outage/2023/07/26/intermittent-performance-issues</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>outage</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Scheduler Outage on 7/25/23 at 6:00PM</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Starting at 6:00PM on Tuesday, July 25th, the SLURM scheduler will go offline in order to perform a migration of its underlying compute resources. This migration is necessary to complete routine maintenance on underlying compute resources. This outage is expected to last up to 30 minutes. During this time, SLURM client commands (sbatch, squeue, etc.) will be unavailable and no new jobs will be started. Queued and running jobs will not be affected. If you have any question about this outage, &lt;a href=&quot;https://contact.icer.msu.edu/&quot;&gt;please contact us&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2023 13:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2023/07/11/SLURM-Controller-Outage</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2023/07/11/SLURM-Controller-Outage</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>maintenance</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Minor SLURM Update on 7/10/23</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;On Monday, July 10th, we will be deploying a minor update to the SLURM scheduling software. This update contains a patch designed to address a bug experienced with some large jobs (&amp;gt;50 nodes) that causes job processes to persist past a job’s end time. If you have any questions about this update or you experience issues following this update, please contact us at https://contact.icer.msu.edu/.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2023 13:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2023/07/06/Minor-SLURM-Update</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2023/07/06/Minor-SLURM-Update</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>maintenance</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Minor Singularity Update on 7/3/23</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;On Monday, July 3rd, we will be deploying a minor update to the Singularity container software. This update will bring the HPCC from version 3.11.2 to the latest 3.11.4. Several bug fixes and new features are available in this version. For a full list of changes, please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sylabs/singularity/releases&quot;&gt;Singularity’s release notes on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;. If you have any questions about this update or you experience issues following this update, &lt;a href=&quot;https://contact.icer.msu.edu/&quot;&gt;please contact us&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2023 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2023/06/29/Minor-Singularity-Update</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2023/06/29/Minor-Singularity-Update</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>maintenance</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Minor SLURM Update on 6/28/23</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;On Wednesday, June 28th, we will be deploying a minor update to the SLURM scheduling software. This update contains minor bug fixes and should not impact HPCC users. If you have any questions about this update or you experience issues following this update, please contact us at https://contact.icer.msu.edu/.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2023 13:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2023/06/27/Minor-SLURM-Update</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2023/06/27/Minor-SLURM-Update</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>maintenance</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>HPCC Connectivity Issues - UPDATED</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;UPDATE: Network connectivity has been restored, and all ICER services are operational.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At approximately 12:30 pm on 23 June, 2023 we experienced a service interruption in the HPCC.  The situation is still ongoing, and we will post an update when service is restored or additional information is available.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2023 15:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/outage/2023/06/23/HPCC-connectivity-issues</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/outage/2023/06/23/HPCC-connectivity-issues</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>outage</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
