<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ICER Announcements Blog</title>
    <description>We'll post information about ICER's system downtimes,  updates, new features, and other information for the ICER user community here.
</description>
    <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//</link>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.icer.msu.edu//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2023 15:07:14 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2023 15:07:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.2.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>HPCC Scheduled Downtime</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The HPCC will be unavailable on Tuesday, August 8th for our regularly scheduled maintenance.  No jobs will run during this time. Jobs that will not be completed before August 8th will not begin until after maintenance is complete. For example, if you submit a four day job three days before the maintenance outage, your job will be postponed and will not begin to run until after maintenance is completed.
If you have any questions, &lt;a href=&quot;https://contact.icer.msu.edu/&quot;&gt;please contact us&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2023 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/2023/07/24/Summer-Maintenance</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/2023/07/24/Summer-Maintenance</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Scheduler Outage on 7/25/23 at 6:00PM</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Starting at 6:00PM on Tuesday, July 25th, the SLURM scheduler will go offline in order to perform a migration of its underlying compute resources. This migration is necessary to complete routine maintenance on underlying compute resources. This outage is expected to last up to 30 minutes. During this time, SLURM client commands (sbatch, squeue, etc.) will be unavailable and no new jobs will be started. Queued and running jobs will not be affected. If you have any question about this outage, &lt;a href=&quot;https://contact.icer.msu.edu/&quot;&gt;please contact us&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2023 13:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2023/07/11/SLURM-Controller-Outage</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2023/07/11/SLURM-Controller-Outage</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>maintenance</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Minor SLURM Update on 7/10/23</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;On Monday, July 10th, we will be deploying a minor update to the SLURM scheduling software. This update contains a patch designed to address a bug experienced with some large jobs (&amp;gt;50 nodes) that causes job processes to persist past a job’s end time. If you have any questions about this update or you experience issues following this update, please contact us at https://contact.icer.msu.edu/.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2023 13:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2023/07/06/Minor-SLURM-Update</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2023/07/06/Minor-SLURM-Update</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>maintenance</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Minor Singularity Update on 7/3/23</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;On Monday, July 3rd, we will be deploying a minor update to the Singularity container software. This update will bring the HPCC from version 3.11.2 to the latest 3.11.4. Several bug fixes and new features are available in this version. For a full list of changes, please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sylabs/singularity/releases&quot;&gt;Singularity’s release notes on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;. If you have any questions about this update or you experience issues following this update, &lt;a href=&quot;https://contact.icer.msu.edu/&quot;&gt;please contact us&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2023 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2023/06/29/Minor-Singularity-Update</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2023/06/29/Minor-Singularity-Update</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>maintenance</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Minor SLURM Update on 6/28/23</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;On Wednesday, June 28th, we will be deploying a minor update to the SLURM scheduling software. This update contains minor bug fixes and should not impact HPCC users. If you have any questions about this update or you experience issues following this update, please contact us at https://contact.icer.msu.edu/.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2023 13:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2023/06/27/Minor-SLURM-Update</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/maintenance/2023/06/27/Minor-SLURM-Update</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>maintenance</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>HPCC Connectivity Issues - UPDATED</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;UPDATE: Network connectivity has been restored, and all ICER services are operational.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At approximately 12:30 pm on 23 June, 2023 we experienced a service interruption in the HPCC.  The situation is still ongoing, and we will post an update when service is restored or additional information is available.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2023 15:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/outage/2023/06/23/HPCC-connectivity-issues</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/outage/2023/06/23/HPCC-connectivity-issues</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>outage</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Server Maintenance on June 22 at 5:30AM - UPDATED</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;UPDATE: This maintenance work is now complete.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are currently experiencing issues with a server that hosts one of the HPCC gateway nodes, along with a few other HPCC services. Between 5:30AM and 6:15AM on June 22, 2023, this server will be rebooted. The HPCC will still be accessible during this time via one of our other gateways, although you may receive a time-out while the server is rebooted. If you receive a connection time-out during this time while attempting to connect to the HPCC, please continue trying to connect until you are redirected to a still active gateway node.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An update will be posted here when service is 100% restored.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2023 19:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/2023/06/21/Server-Maintenance-06-22-At-0530AM</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/2023/06/21/Server-Maintenance-06-22-At-0530AM</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Performance problem on home system, possible hardware issue, HPCC investigating - UPDATED</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;UPDATE: The performance issues with the home directory system have been resolved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UPDATE: We’ve identified a likely problem and are working with the storage vendor to confirm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are currently seeing performance issues with the home directory system due to possible hardware issues. An update will be posted once remediation steps have been identified.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2023 14:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/2023/06/16/Home-Directory-Performance-Issues-Updated</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/2023/06/16/Home-Directory-Performance-Issues-Updated</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Network Maintenance Planned for June 19, 2023 at 6:30PM - UPDATED</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;UPDATE: Scheduled HPCC network maintenance is now complete.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Monday, June 19, 2023 at 6:30PM an update will be applied to a limited number of services in our networking infrastructure. A brief outage of only a few milliseconds for anyone attempting to connect to the HPCC at 6:30PM is anticipated while this update runs. An update to the blog will be posted when maintenance is complete.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2023 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/2023/06/15/Network-Maintenance-Planned-June-19-2023</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/2023/06/15/Network-Maintenance-Planned-June-19-2023</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Email Delivery Delays - June 5, 2023 - UPDATED</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;UPDATE: Email to ICER is now functioning again without errors or delays.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are currently seeing performance issues with one of the University’s third-party email providers. This issue is impacting email delivery to ICER, including contact form requests and responses to incident tickets. If you receive a bounceback error message upon emailing ICER, know that delivery for your message may be delayed, but delivery will be re-attempted for up to 5 days. We will post an update as soon as this issue is resolved.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2023 19:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/2023/06/05/Email-Delivery-Delay-Updated</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.icer.msu.edu//announcement/2023/06/05/Email-Delivery-Delay-Updated</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
